Toggle Navigation

Destinations

### Destinations

* Back

Other Holdings

### Other Holdings

* Back

* * *

PREVIEW MODE OFF

Privacy Policy
==============

**EFFECTIVE: January 2004  
UPDATED: February 2024**

Alterra Mountain Company is committed to the privacy of our guests, pass holders and homeowners (“you” and “your”). The Alterra Mountain Company Privacy Policy (the “Policy”) applies to Personal Information that Alterra Mountain Company collects online, in person, and through its call centers or otherwise.

“Personal Information” means data that classifies as personal information, personal data, personally identifiable information, or similar terms under applicable data privacy and security laws and regulations. Personal Information does not include data excluded or exempted from those laws and regulations, such as aggregated, anonymized, or deidentified information that cannot be associated with a specific individual.

“Alterra Mountain Company”, “we”, “us” or “our” refers to Alterra Mountain Company, its subsidiaries, including its mountain resorts, Ikon Pass, Ski Butlers and certain of their affiliates. We have an international presence and maintain offices and facilities in multiple jurisdictions throughout the United States and Canada. Except in circumstances where the privacy policy of an affiliate, third party, or partner applies, all of our business operations are subject to this Policy. For a complete list of Alterra Mountain Company resorts and assets, please visit alterramtnco.com.

This Policy does not apply to information about Alterra Mountain Company’s employees or to information that is not Personal Information. Alterra Mountain Company employees should consult the Team Member Privacy Policy for information on workplace privacy.

**POLICY CONTENT**

1. [PERSONAL INFORMATION WE COLLECT AND HOW IT IS USED](#privacy-personal-information)
    1. [We collect your Personal Information when you purchase a product or service, make a reservation, visit our resorts or enroll in a program.](#a-personal-information)
    2. [We collect your Personal Information when you visit our resorts and websites, and use our pass and ticket products.](#b-personal-information)
    3. [We collect your Personal Information when you download and use our web or mobile applications (“Apps”).](#c-personal-information)
    4. [We collect your Personal Information when you submit an inquiry, participate in a chat session, complete a guest survey, or provide feedback.](#d-personal-information)
    5. [We collect your Personal Information when you participate in a marketing initiative or create an online account.](#e-personal-information)
    6. [We collect your Personal Information when you call our call centers or when we call you.](#f-personal-information)
    7. [We collect your Personal Information from service providers and other third parties.](#g-personal-information)
2. [OUR COLLECTION OF INFORMATION THROUGH COOKIES AND OTHER TRACKING TECHNOLOGIES](#cookies-and-tracking-technologies)
3. [WHEN WE MAY COMBINE YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION](#combine-personal-information)
4. [WHEN WE SHARE PERSONAL INFORMATION](#share-personal-information)
5. [YOUR CONSENT](#consent)
6. [HOW TO MANAGE YOUR MARKETING PREFERENCES](#manage-marketing-preferences)
7. [CHILDREN'S PRIVACY](#children-privacy)
8. [HOW LONG WE KEEP YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION](#how-long-we-keep-information)
9. [HOW WE PROTECT YOUR INFORMATION](#protect-your-information)
10. [WHERE WE STORE YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION](#storage-of-personal-information)
11. [YOUR PRIVACY OPTIONS AND RIGHTS](#your-privacy-options)
    1. [_California Customers_](#california-customers)
    2. _[Colorado, Connecticut, Utah, and Virginia Customers](#colorado-connecticut-utah-virginia-customers)_
    3. [_European Union, Switzerland and United Kingdom Customers_](#european-switzerland-uk-customers)
12. [THIRD PARTY LINKS](#third-party-links)
13. [SUBJECT TO CHANGE](#subject-to-change)
14. [CONTACT US](#contact-us)

**1\. PERSONAL INFORMATION WE COLLECT AND HOW IT IS USED**

Alterra Mountain Company collects Personal Information during the course of operating our mountain resort adventure, resort hospitality, and real estate businesses, including through our Apps, websites, and when you interact with us otherwise (collectively, the “**Services**”). We use this information to provide you with the best possible service, facilitate your purchase of a product or service, and to meet our reasonable business needs.

_(a) We collect your Personal Information when you purchase a product or service, make a reservation, visit our resorts or enroll in a program._

When you purchase a product or service, make a reservation, visit our resorts or enroll in a program, we collect Personal Information in order to process the transaction and administer the purchase, reservation or program and depending on your marketing preferences, to send you personalized communications about products and services that we think might be of interest to you. We may also send you communications relating to your purchase, reservation or participation in a program. For example, if you make a reservation at one of our resorts, we may send you information about the activities, events or offers taking place at the resort around the time of your visit.

The Personal Information we may collect and use for these purposes of administering our Services includes your:

* name and contact information to identify and communicate with you;
* payment card information to process transactions;
* age and/or birth date to ensure appropriate product pricing and know more about who is enjoying our products and services;
* gender to verify your identity, provide appropriate services, such as rental equipment, and know more about who is enjoying our products and services;
* information regarding your physical characteristics when this information is necessary in connection with the product, service, program or activity that you have requested (for example, we may need your height, weight and shoe size to provide you with appropriate rental equipment);
* health/medical information (such as, allergies or medical conditions that we need to be aware if you are participating in lessons or other programs, or if you have dietary restrictions);
* facial photograph to identify you as a pass holder;
* status as the parent or guardian of a minor guest, if applicable;
* skier or experience preferences (such as, preferred lodging room type, whether you are a skier or snowboarder) to know more about who is enjoying our products and services and how we can improve our products and services;
* demographic information including your race to learn more about who is enjoying our products and services and how we can improve our products and services;
* income and education information to learn more about who is enjoying our products and services and how we can improve our products and services;
* social security or social insurance numbers or other tax identification numbers of our homeowners who participate in our homeowner rental management program so that we can process the payment of your rental revenue;
* geographic location to locate ski school participants or other guests who have elected to utilize on-mountain tracking technology while at our resorts, including our Apps that offer on-mountain tracking; and
* purchase and transaction history to manage your purchases and reservations and to learn more about how you interact with our products and services or the products and services of industry vendors and partners.

In some cases, you may provide us with Personal Information relating to a family member or another individual. By providing us with Personal Information relating to an individual other than yourself, you represent that you have their consent to provide us with their Personal Information for the purposes described in this Policy.

We may use this Personal Information for targeted advertising and sales, and we may sell or share it with Industry Partners and Pass Product Resorts (defined below).

_(b) We collect your Personal Information when you visit our resorts and websites, and use our pass, frequency and ticket products and other services._

When you purchase or use our pass, frequency and ticket products, we may collect information regarding your geographic location, activities, gate scans and purchases while you are at Alterra Mountain Company resorts. Our pass products and tickets use either handheld scanner or RFID (radio frequency identification) technology. Through the use of this technology, we may be able to collect limited information regarding your visit at a resort, including the gate scans and lifts that you ride, and depending on whether you have a payment card linked to your pass product, other commercial transactions that you complete at our retail or restaurant locations. We use this information to understand how our guests use our resorts and to understand your personal preferences, which help us to improve our products and services.

Depending on your marketing preferences, we may also use your Personal Information to send you offers, invitations or promotions relating to our resorts, products, services or programs that we believe may be of interest to you. For example, we may use information from your purchase history at our resorts or your interactions with our websites to send you personalized or special offers and promotions.

Some of our pass products grant you access to ski resorts that are not owned or operated by Alterra Mountain Company (each a “**Pass Product Resort**”). When you use your pass at a Pass Product Resort, the Pass Product Resort will scan or otherwise record your attendance at that resort location using RFID technology (radio frequency identification), handheld scanners, or another method which allows the Pass Product Resort and us to record your use of the pass product. We may also share your Personal Information with a Pass Product Resort to administer your pass product, better understand how you use your pass products, and learn about how we can improve the guest experience.

Several of our resort locations use GPS tracking technology in connection with their ski and ride school programs in order to track and locate students on the mountain. The GPS tracking technology is owned and operated by a third-party service provider that may be provided certain Personal Information, including name and email address, to provide the tracking service and to facilitate the use of its website on which you and/or your family members can track your school day on the mountain.

At certain of our resort locations, we may use web cams and video surveillance for the safety and security of our guests, employees and property, and to better understand how many and when guests are visiting our resort locations so that we can make operational decisions, including decisions regarding staffing and hours of operation. We will retain video surveillance recordings for as long as reasonably necessary for these purposes. Our resort locations may also use live stream webcams in outdoor public areas either on mountain or in the base village area. These live web cam feeds can be accessed by anyone via an internet connection and in some situations, your image or personally identifying traits may be temporarily displayed in web cam footage.

If you rent or demo equipment from one of our resort locations or businesses, we will collect Personal Information, including physical characteristics and skier preferences, in order to fit your equipment and rent it to you.

We may use this Personal Information for targeted advertising and sales, and we may sell or share it with Industry Partners and Pass Product Resorts.

_(c) We collect your Personal Information when you download and use our web or mobile applications (“**Apps**”)._

Some of our resorts and products have Apps available for download to your mobile device. The download, installation and use of our Apps will allow you convenient access to great experiences our resorts have to offer, including the ability to create a profile and purchase pass products, lift tickets, track and share your performance, create social groups with whom you can share information (including geolocation information), earn achievement badges, post chat communications to others in your social groups participate in contests and events, access mountain wayfinding, weather and lift info, and receive in-App notifications (collectively, the “**App Services**”). If you access our Apps, we may be able to collect your Personal Information, including your precise geographic location, activity information (including rate of speed), purchase history, and interaction with the Apps depending on your App settings. Our privacy nutrition labels and data safety disclosures can be accessed on the App Store or on Google Play. We may also associate the information collected through your use of the Apps to your customer profile, including your pass product and pass scan data.

The Apps automatically collect detailed location and navigation information, in the form of GPS signals from the mobile device on which you have installed and activated the Apps (“**App Location Information**”). Whenever you open, use or interact with the App Services, we use your App Location Information (e.g., latitude and longitude) to tailor the App Services experience to your current location. We also use your App Location Information to provide certain App Services, including to send you notifications of friends, events, or other relevant information that are near to you. If you have ‘background location’ turned on, the Apps may, from time to time, tell us about your device’s location even if you are not directly interacting with the Apps. We may use various technologies to determine your App Location Information, such as location services of the applicable operating system or browser, GPS, Bluetooth, i-Beacon, RFID, and sensor data from your devices, along with nearby Wi-Fi access points and cell towers, and other technologies to determine your mobile devices' approximate location.

The Apps may also share your App Location Information on a map or by communicating your distance and general direction to other users. You should only share your App Location Information with those that you trust. You understand that the nature of location-based services is such that your App Location Information is available to you and other users, and that we cannot control what you or other users, who receive this information when using the Apps or the App Services, will do with it.

If you do not wish for the Apps to track your App Location Information, you should turn off the App Location Information tracking feature in the Apps’ settings menu. If you turn off the App Location Information feature, some features of the Apps and App Services cannot be provided without using this standard technology. For example, the App Services use your location and route information to create a detailed location history of your journeys made when using the Apps and App Services. The Apps use this history to offer the App Services to you, to improve the quality of the App Services it offers to you and to all of its users and to improve the accuracy of its mapping and navigation data.

You may be able to take part in certain activities within our App Services that let you communicate or share information not just with us, but also with other users. These include:

* sending private or group messages or content to other users
* chatting with other users
* sharing performance metrics, such as your total days skied, vertical feet skied, and number of chairlift rides
* sharing your skill-level, home mountain, and/or personal preferences
* sharing photos or drawings with other users.

We record and store archives of this data on servers to provide these features as well as to protect our rights and property in connection with our App Services and you acknowledge and agree to our storage of this data.

We may use this Personal Information for targeted advertising and sales, and we may sell or share it with Industry Partners and Pass Product Resorts.

_(d) We collect your Personal Information when you submit an inquiry, participate in a chat session, complete a guest survey, or provide feedback._

We may collect your name, contact information and comments or questions when you submit an inquiry or comment, participate in a chat session, or otherwise provide us with feedback about our business. If you engage with the ChatBot feature on our websites, we will record the conversation. Please note that the ChatBot is an automated program and not a real person, and information relating to your communications may be shared with our service provider.

We may also collect information related to your experience at one of our resort locations or using our products or services in a guest satisfaction survey. These surveys may include optional questions regarding your income, education, race/ethnicity, or gender which, if answered, help us to learn more about our customers and how we can improve our business and public engagement and diversity, equity and inclusion in snow sports. We may use this information to respond to your question and to improve our business, products, services and programs.

_(e) We collect your Personal Information when you participate in a marketing initiative or create an online account._

If you choose to create an online account profile, we may collect your name, contact information, age, gender, birth date, personal image, username and password and other information that you choose to provide (such as your snow sport preferences).

We may also collect your name, contact information, age and/or date of birth if you decide to participate in a marketing initiative such as a contest, sweepstakes or other promotion. In some cases, we may also ask you specific questions about your preferences or for feedback on our business, products, services and programs. We use this information to administer the promotion, including contacting and announcing winners (where applicable), to improve our business, products, services and programs, and for marketing initiatives, such as offers or promotions relating to our resorts, products, services, or programs that we believe may be of interest to you, depending on your marketing preferences.

_(f) We collect your Personal Information when you call our call centers or when we call you._

We may record calls into and out of our call centers for the purpose of maintaining accurate records and for quality assurance and training purposes. We will retain call recordings for as long as reasonably necessary for these purposes.

_(g) We collect your Personal Information from service providers and other third parties._

If you are a resident of the U.S., we may also supplement the Personal Information that you provide to us with information that we obtain from third parties.

**2\. OUR COLLECTION OF INFORMATION THROUGH COOKIES AND OTHER TRACKING TECHNOLOGIES**

When you visit one of our websites or use one of our Apps, your web browser sends us certain information depending on the browser you use and your privacy and security settings. This information may include your IP address, the name and version of your operating system, the name and version of your web browser, other technical data information, whether you accessed our website from a computer or a mobile device, when you open emails we send you, the date, time, and duration of your visit, and geolocation data. We may also use session replay tools on our websites and in our Apps to record your interactions with the websites and Apps, such as how you move throughout the websites and Apps and how you engage with our webforms. Web browser data and session replay tools help with system administration, traffic reposting, and auditing. It also helps us better understand who our guests are, how they use our products and services, and what we can do to improve the user experience. We may use this information to offer you products and services and to create aggregate statistics. This helps us improve your experience both online and at our resorts.

We also use “cookies,” including pixels, to customize your website user experience by tailoring online content to align with your browsing habits. Cookies are small pieces of data, stored on your hard drive that send us information about your online browsing habits, including login and browsing history, button impressions, and personal preferences. Cookies also tell us under which account a user is logged in to one of our websites and this information helps us protect your information by making sure your personal preferences are only displayed when you are actually logged in. If you tell an Alterra Mountain Company website to “Remember Me” or save your preferences, this information is stored using a cookie. Some cookies are also required to support the functionality of your transaction (e.g., putting items in your shopping cart).

We engage third parties to display advertisements on our behalf and to provide analytics data. These third parties include advertising networks (such as Google AdWords and Facebook Ads) that use cookies, pixels, and similar technologies to track your engagement with our advertisements and to track your use of our websites and other websites. These cookies, pixels, and similar technologies help advertising networks to provide advertisements about products and services tailored to your inferred interest and to provide us with information on how you interact with the content on our websites. For example, the webpage content that you click on, the duration of your visit to our website, and what website you visited prior to ours.

This advertising may appear on our website(s) or on other websites. Some of our advertising network’s technology uses separate cookies or other tracking technologies, including pixels, that may be delivered to your device when you visit our websites, purchase our products, use our Apps, or open emails from us. These advertising technologies are governed by the individual third-party advertising network’s privacy policy. Some of these third-party ad networks may be members of the Network Advertising Initiative (NAI). If they are members of NAI, then you have the option to “opt out.” Additional information on NAI members and how to opt out, can be found at [https://thenai.org/opt-out.](https://thenai.org/opt-out.)

The following chart lists the different types of cookies that we and our service providers use on our websites and Apps, examples of those who serves those cookies and links to the privacy notices and opt-out information of those cookie servers. Because the specific cookies and pixels we may use vary over time, as well as differ by the specific page you are browsing, the below chart is illustrative only.

| Types of Cookies | Purpose | Who Serves (for example) |
| --- | --- | --- |
| * * * | * * * | * * * |
| Required | These cookies are required for the operation of the Services and enable you to move around the Services and use its features. These cookies also enable your interactions with the Services such as emailing us and customer support chat. Disabling these cookies can negatively impact the performance of Services. | Alterra Mountain Company, Adobe, Google, Microsoft, OneTrust |
| * * * | * * * | * * * |
| Performance | These cookies are required for the operation of the Services and enable you to move around the Services and use its features.  Disabling these cookies can negatively impact the performance of Services. These cookies, beacons, and pixels allow us to analyze activities on the Services.  They can be used to improve the functioning of the Services.  For example, these cookies recognize and count the number of visitors and see how they move around the Services.  Analytics cookies also help us measure the performance of our advertising campaigns to help us improve them and to optimize the content on the Services for those who engage with our advertising. | Adobe, Google, Hoefler&Co., Mapbox, Hotjar, Meta, Microsoft, Pingdom, Pinterest, TikTok, Yahoo! |
| * * * | * * * | * * * |
| Marketing | These cookies and pixels are used to deliver relevant ads, track ad campaign performance, or track email marketing.  These cookies are used to enable you to share pages and content that you find interesting on our Services through third-party social networking and other websites.  These cookies may also be used for advertising purposes. | Google, LinkedIn, Meta, Pinterest, Reddit, Snapchat, TikTok, TV Squared, X, Fyllo, Index Exchange, Jivox, LiveRamp, OpenX, PubMatric, SpotX, StackAdapt, Rubicon, Tapad, TradeDesk, Xandr, Yahoo! |

**Managing Your Cookies -** You can choose to disable some or all cookies using your web browser’s preferences menu or the “Your Privacy Choices” link in the footer of our websites. By turning off cookies, we will still be able to track your browsing history during a single visit to one of our websites, however, we will not be able to link your browsing history during each of these visits to you, as you will be considered a new visitor each time you visit one of our websites. Be aware that turning off cookies may disable certain functions on the website and cause it not to function properly.

**Do our Websites and Apps Respond to “Do Not Track” Signals?**

We recognize the Global Privacy Control (“**GPC**”). Your browser must be able to support the GPC for us to recognize your opt-out preference signal.

**3\. WHEN WE MAY COMBINE YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION**

We may combine the Personal Information that you provide, or that we collect, to better understand your needs, requirements, and personal preferences so that we may improve our business, products, services and programs and optimize your experience when you visit our resort locations, or when you are dealing with one of our team members, a call center representative, agents or other authorized third party.

Depending on your marketing preferences, we may also use this information to send you offers, invitations or promotions relating to our resorts, products, services or programs that we believe may be of interest to you. For example, we may evaluate your commercial transactions or browsing habits on our websites or at our resorts which may influence the personalized special offers and promotions that we send to you.

**4\. WHEN WE SHARE PERSONAL INFORMATION**

We may provide your Personal Information to service providers and other third parties in the following circumstances:

* **Vendors** – We may share your Personal Information with vendors (including affiliates acting in this capacity) who provide services on our behalf such as payment card processors, call center administrators, web-site hosting service providers, app developers, and data management, identity verification (for example, to confirm your eligibility for special offers, such as military discounts), market analyses, marketing, advertising and contest administration vendors, or your Personal Information may be collected by such service providers on our behalf.
* **Industry Partners** - We may disclose your Personal Information to third-party partners in situations where the disclosure is necessary to complete or provide the service, product (such as, a pass product), or information that you have purchased or requested, or it is intended to optimize the service, product, or information that you have purchased, inquired about, or requested. For example, we may disclose your Personal Information to a third-party tour operator if you purchased a tour from the third-party tour operator using one of our resort’s websites.
* **Pass Product Resorts** - When you scan certain pass products at Pass Product Resorts, we may disclose your Personal Information to Pass Product Resorts that are outside of the family of Alterra Mountain Company-owned and operated resorts to administer your pass product. When you scan your pass at a Pass Product Resort, you should consult that resort’s privacy policy.
* **Other Entities in the Alterra Mountain Company Group of Companies** – Personal Information relating to Alterra Mountain Company customers is maintained in a database that is accessible to the Alterra Mountain Company group of companies. We may combine that information with other information we collect about you, but we will always use the information as described in this Policy. This means that Personal Information collected by one of our subsidiaries may be used to send you communications regarding another subsidiary or businesses within our group of companies. The purpose of this sharing is to facilitate customer bookings and reservations across all our resorts and, depending on your marketing preferences, allow our businesses to better understand your preferences and send you information about our resorts, products, services and programs.
* **Alterra Mountain Company Community Foundation** – we may disclose limited personal information about you, such as your name, email and product purchased, to the Alterra Mountain Company Community Foundation for internal recordkeeping and future donations, as permitted by law.
* **Corporate Transactions** – We may disclose your Personal Information to another entity, if necessary, in the event of an actual or proposed merger, sale, corporate transaction, re-organization, including as part of insolvency or bankruptcy proceedings, or similar type of transaction, or for the purposes of evaluating and/or performing such transaction. Additionally, if we are entering into a corporate transaction with a third party, we may receive Personal Information in connection with the diligence. If we close a transaction, the third party may transfer Personal Information, which we would use as described in this Policy.
* **Special Circumstances** – We may consider it necessary or may be required by law to disclose your Personal Information with our attorneys, with others who are legally authorized in certain emergencies where, in our reasonable opinion, the health, safety or well-being of a person is at imminent risk, with law enforcement or other parties to comply with a court order, such as a subpoena, or as otherwise is required to comply with the law.

**5\. YOUR CONSENT**

We collect, use and disclose your Personal Information as outlined in this Policy and with your consent, except where permitted or required otherwise by law. We may be required or permitted under statute or regulation to collect, use or disclose Personal Information without your consent, for example to comply with a court order, to collect a debt owed to us or if there is an imminent threat to an individual’s health, safety, or well-being.

Your consent may be express (for example, oral, written, or electronic) or your consent may be reasonably inferred or implied from something that you do (for example, use of our websites implies consent to the collection, use and disclosure of your Personal Information as described in this Policy). In some instances, an authorized representative may consent on your behalf. In the case of minor children, a parent or legal guardian may consent to our collection, use and disclosure of a minor’s Personal Information in connection with the purchase and administration of a product, such as a pass product or service. For more information about how we obtain parental consent, please see the “Children’s Privacy” section below.

You may withdraw your consent at any time, subject to legal or contractual restraints, by contacting us at the locations listed in the “Your Privacy Options” section of this Policy. However, your withdrawal of consent might affect your experience and our ability to provide products or services to you, or quick and accurate service to you either online or through our service agents.

If you do not consent to the collection, use and disclosure of your Personal Information online as described in this Policy, do not use our websites, Apps or purchase our products or services.

**6\. HOW TO MANAGE YOUR MARKETING PREFERENCES**

If you no longer want us to use your Personal Information for marketing purposes, including to send you promotional communications, you may contact us at the locations listed in the “Your Privacy Options” section of this Policy and ask to be removed from our mailing and/or contact lists. We may ask you for more information where required in order to identify you correctly. If you unsubscribe from marketing communications, please note that we may still need to contact you regarding other matters such as those relating to a purchase transaction or the administration of your pass.

You may also manage your email subscriptions by clicking on “Unsubscribe” at the bottom of any of our emails you receive to stop receiving future promotional email communications from us.

If you wish to stop receiving text messages from us, please reply “STOP” to the text message.

**7\. CHILDREN'S PRIVACY**

**Children Under 13:** We do not knowingly collect Personal Information from children under the age of thirteen, without obtaining verified, prior consent of the child’s parent or legal guardian. Alterra Mountain Company’s websites and social media pages available online and Apps are not directed to users under the age of thirteen. This Policy, along with any additional parental consent forms provided as part of the provision of the Services to children, describes our privacy practices including the way we collect and process your child’s information. If you believe that your child under the age of thirteen may have provided us with Personal Information online, please contact us at [yourprivacy@alterramtnco.com](mailto:yourprivacy@alterramtnco.com) and we will take appropriate action.

We require the consent of the child’s parent or guardian for a child under the age of 13 to open an account or create profile related to an App. Parents and guardians understand the App may collect information about their child, such as photos, chat sessions, location information and the lifts that the child has skied or snowboarded. We collect this information for the limited purpose of providing the App Services. We do not collect or use this information to market products or services to children, and we will not sell this information. You may request deletion of your child’s Personal Information at any time. You have the right to consent to our collection and use of your child’s Personal Information while withholding consent for disclosure of that Personal Information to third parties. You may review, delete or prohibit further collection of your child’s Personal Information at any time. To disable your child’s account, request a copy of the information, or ask a question about the Apps and your child’s data, parents and guardians should contact our Chief Privacy Officer at [yourprivacy@alterramtnco.com](mailto:yourprivacy@alterramtnco.com).

**8\. HOW LONG WE KEEP YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION**

We will keep your Personal Information on file for a the period of time for which it is necessary to accomplish the purpose for which it was provided, to meet our business requirements, and fulfill our legal obligations and as applicable, the needs of the parties to whom we disclose it, including Pass Product Resorts. We may retain your Personal Information for longer periods for specific purposes to the extent that we are obliged to do so in accordance with applicable laws and regulations, to protect you, other people, and us from fraud, abuse, unauthorized access, as necessary to protect our legal rights, or for certain business requirements.

We will delete your Personal Information when it is no longer necessary for the purpose for which it was collected, or upon your request, subject to exceptions as discussed in this Policy or under applicable law, contract, or regulation.

If you use our App(s), you can delete your account by deleting your account through the App(s). If you delete your account from within the App(s), we will delete the accompanying Personal Information.

**9\. HOW WE PROTECT YOUR INFORMATION**

The security of your Personal Information is important to us. We take various reasonable, organizational, administrative, and technical measures (described below) to protect your Personal Information from unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, or destruction. However, we cannot and do not guarantee complete security, as it does not exist on the Internet.

If required by law to do so, we will notify you and/or the relevant supervisory authority in the event of a data breach.

Your Personal Information may be maintained on our servers or those of our service providers and accessible by our authorized employees, service providers and representatives. We maintain reasonable and systematic controls, schedules, and practices to retain and destroy Personal Information.

**Internal Protections:** We protect Personal Information by security safeguards appropriate to the sensitivity of the information. We have policies and practices to protect against loss, theft, unauthorized access, disclosure, copying, use, modification, or destruction. While we make efforts to protect your Personal Information, we are not in a position to guarantee that your Personal Information will always be secure. There may be factors beyond our control which may result in loss or theft, or unauthorized access, use or disclosure of your Personal Information. As a consequence, we disclaim any warranties or representation on non-disclosure of your Personal Information. We also employ a Chief Privacy Officer to be accountable for our compliance with these policies and whom you may contact at the address below with any question, concern or complaint.

**External Protections:** To protect information disclosed to service providers, we use contractual or other means to provide a similar level of protection so that service providers treat the information confidentially, implement appropriate security measures and only use and disclose the information for the purposes of providing the applicable services.

**10\. WHERE WE STORE YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION**

Please be aware that your Personal Information may be transferred to, stored and processed by us and our affiliates in Canada and the United States where Alterra Mountain Company, or its affiliates or service providers operate and maintain data. If you are a citizen of a country other than the United States, your Personal Information will be subject to applicable U.S. laws, which may permit foreign government, regulatory or national security authorities to have access to your Personal Information in certain circumstances. By providing us with your Personal Information, you understand and agree that your Personal Information may be transferred to our facilities in the United States, processed by us in the United States, stored in the United States, and transferred to those with whom we share it as described in this Policy.

**11\. YOUR PRIVACY OPTIONS AND RIGHTS**

_(a) California Customers_

If you are a California resident, you have certain rights with respect to the collection, use, transfer, and processing of your Personal Information, as defined by the California Consumer Privacy Act, Cal. Civ. Code § 1798.100 _et seq_., as amended by the California Privacy Rights Act and implementing regulations (collectively the “**CCPA**”). We reserve the right to limit these rights where permitted under applicable law, including where your identity cannot be reasonably verified or to the extent your rights adversely affect the rights and freedoms of others. Please note that terms in this California Privacy Rights section are used in accordance with the definitions provided to them in the CPRA, which may differ from how those terms are used throughout the rest of the Privacy Policy (for example, the word “share”).

**What Information Do We Collect?**

The below examples are illustrative examples from the CCPA and do not reflect the specific pieces of information we collect.

In the previous 12 months, we have collected the following categories of Personal Information:

| Category | Examples | Collected | Retention Period |
| --- | --- | --- | --- |
| * * * | * * * | * * * | * * * |
| A. Identifiers | A real name, alias, postal address, unique personal identifier, online identifier, Internet Protocol address, email address, account name, Social Security number, driver’s license number, passport number, or other similar identifiers. | Yes | To fulfill the business purpose for which it was collected or as required by law |
| * * * | * * * | * * * | * * * |
| B. Personal Information | A name, signature, Social Security number, physical characteristics or description, address, telephone number, mobile phone number, passport number, driver’s license or state identification card number, insurance policy number, education, employment, employment history, bank account number, credit card number, debit card number, or any other financial information, medical information, or health insurance information. Some personal information included in this category may overlap with other categories. | Yes | To fulfill the business purpose for which it was collected or as required by law |
| * * * | * * * | * * * | * * * |
| C. Protected Classification Characteristics Under California or Federal Law | Age (40 years or older), race, color, ancestry, national origin, citizenship, religion or creed, marital status, medical condition, physical or mental disability, sex (including gender, gender identity, gender expression, pregnancy or childbirth and related medical conditions), sexual orientation, veteran or military status, genetic information (including familial genetic information). | Yes | To fulfill the business purpose for which it was collected or as required by law |
| * * * | * * * | * * * | * * * |
| D. Commercial Information | Records of personal property, products or services purchased, obtained, or considered, or other purchasing or consuming histories or tendencies. | Yes | To fulfill the business purpose for which it was collected or as required by law |
| * * * | * * * | * * * | * * * |
| E. Biometric Information | Physiological and behavioral, characteristics, such as, health, weight, shoe size, or exercise data. | Yes | To fulfill the business purpose for which it was collected or as required by law |
| * * * | * * * | * * * | * * * |
| F. Internet or Other Similar Network Activity | Browsing history, search history, information on a consumer’s interaction with a website, application, or advertisement. | Yes | To fulfill the business purpose for which it was collected or as required by law |
| * * * | * * * | * * * | * * * |
| G. Geolocation Data | Physical location or movements. | Yes | To fulfill the business purpose for which it was collected or as required by law |
| * * * | * * * | * * * | * * * |
| H. Sensory Data | Audio, electronic, visual, or similar information, such as use of CCTV cameras or other technology. | Yes | To fulfill the business purpose for which it was collected or as required by law |
| * * * | * * * | * * * | * * * |
| I. Professional or Employment-Related Information | Salary or income level | No  | N/A |
| * * * | * * * | * * * | * * * |
| J. Non-Public Education Information | Education level achieved. | No  | N/A |
| * * * | * * * | * * * | * * * |
| K. Inferences Drawn of the Consumer | Inferences drawn from personal information identified above to create a profile about a consumer reflecting a consumer’s preferences, characteristics, psychological trends, predispositions, behavior, attitudes, intelligence, abilities, and aptitudes. | Yes | To fulfill the business purpose for which it was collected or as required by law |
| * * * | * * * | * * * | * * * |
| L. Sensitive Personal Information | Personal information that reveals (a) Social Security, driver’s license, state identification card, or passport number; (b) account log-in, financial account, debit card, or credit card number in combination with any required security or access code, password, or credential allowing access to an account; (c) precise geolocation; (d) racial or ethnic origin, religious or philosophical beliefs, or union membership; (e) the contents of a consumer’s mail, email, and text messages unless the business is the intended recipient of the communication; or (f) genetic data. Biometric information processed for the purpose of uniquely identifying a consumer, personal information collected and analyzed concerning a consumer’s health, sex life, or sexual orientation. Some Sensitive Personal Information included in this category may overlap with other categories. | Yes | To fulfill the business purpose for which it was collected or as required by law |

**Sources From Which Personal Information Is Collected**

We collect your Personal Information directly from you, from your interaction with our websites, Apps, and Services, from publicly available sources, and from third parties which collect the personal information directly from you.

**Business or Commercial Purposes for Which Personal Information Is Collected**

Your Personal Information is used for the following purposes:

* To present our Services, our websites and Apps and their contents in a suitable and effective manner for you and your device;
* To comply with the law;
* To contact you to provide you with information or services that you request from us;
* To advertise opportunities, services, or special events that we think may be of interest to you;
* To provide customer support, troubleshoot issues, manage accounts, and respond to requests, questions, or comments;
* To carry out our obligations and enforce our rights arising from any contracts; and
* To notify you about any additions, upgrades, or changes in our services.

**Third Parties with Whom Personal Information Is Disclosed, Shared, or Sold**

In the preceding 12 months, we have disclosed the following personal information about consumers for business purposes:

* We disclose Personal Information in categories A (Identifiers), B (Personal), C (Protected Classification), D (Commercial), F (Internet), G (Geolocation), K (Inferences), and L (Sensitive Personal Information) with service providers. We disclose content posted on our social media platforms (_e.g_., if a consumer “comments” on a story) with other consumers. Such posts may include Personal Information in categories A and B, but the content depends on the individual posts.
* We may disclose all of your information, including your Personal Information, to our subsidiaries and affiliates in connection with providing the Services to you or otherwise in connection with business operations.

In the preceding 12 months, we have shared for cross-contextual behavioral advertising the following the Personal Information in categories A (Identifiers), B (Personal), D (Commercial), F (Internet), G (Geolocation), and K (Inferences).

In the preceding twelve (12) months, we have not sold the Personal Information of any consumer for monetary consideration. However, our use of cookies and other tracking technologies may be considered a sale of Personal Information under the CCPA. Categories of Personal Information that we have sold under the CCPA include categories A (Identifiers), B (Personal), D (Commercial), F (Internet), G (Geolocation), and K (Inferences). Categories of third parties to whom Personal Information is sold under the CCPA include data analytics providers and advertising and marketing providers.

You can opt out of our tracking technologies for analytics and advertising service providers by clicking the “Your Privacy Choices” link in the footer of our websites. Please note that your use of our website will still be tracked by Alterra Mountain Company and its service providers.

We do not have actual knowledge that we sell or share the Personal Information of consumers under sixteen (16) years of age.

**Individual Rights**

a. Right to Know About Personal Information Collected, Disclosed, Shared, or Sold

You have the right to request that we disclose the Personal Information we collect, use, and disclose about you to third parties. There are two types of Rights to Know requests that you can make:

1. Right to Know (Abbreviated Request): If you make a Right to Know (Abbreviated Request), you will receive the following information about you:
    1. Categories of Personal Information collected, sold, or shared;
    2. Categories of sources from which Personal Information is collected;
    3. Categories of third parties to whom the information is sold, shared or disclosed;
    4. Business or commercial purpose for collecting, sharing, or selling Personal Information;
    5. Categories of Personal Information disclosed for a business purpose and categories of persons to whom it was disclosed for a business purpose.
2. Right to Know (Specific Pieces of Information Request): If you make a Right to Know (Specific Pieces of Information Request), you will receive the following information about you:
    1. Specific pieces of Personal Information collected about you.

This information will be provided to you free of charge, unless we determine that your request is manifestly unfounded or excessive. You may request this information twice in a 12-month period. There are certain exceptions to a consumer’s Right to Know. We will state in our response if an exception applies.

b. Right of Deletion

You have the right to request that we and our service providers delete any Personal Information about your which we have collected from you upon receipt of a verifiable request. This right is subject to certain exceptions. We will state in our response if an exception applies.

c. Right to Opt-Out of the Sale or Sharing of Personal Information

You have the right to opt-out of the sale or sharing of your Personal Information by a business subject to certain laws and regulations. For more information, please visit our “Your Privacy Choices” link in the footer of our websites. You can also opt out by using the Global Privacy Control signal.

Please note that opt-out choices may be stored via cookies. If you clear cookies, if your browser blocks cookies, or if you view the page from a different browser or device, your opt-out choice may no longer be logged or recognized.

d. Right to Non-Discrimination

You have the right not to receive discriminatory treatment for exercising the privacy rights conferred by California law. We will not discriminate against you because you exercised any of your privacy rights, including, but not limited to, by: denying goods or services to you; charging different prices or rates for goods or services, including through the use of discounts or other benefits or imposing penalties; providing a different level of quality of goods or services to you; or suggesting that you will receive a different price or rate for goods or services or a different level or quality of goods or services. We will also not retaliate against any employee, applicant for employment, or independent contractor for exercising their rights under the CCPA.

e. Right of Correction

If we maintain inaccurate Personal Information about you, then you have the right to request that we correct the inaccurate Personal Information upon receipt of a verifiable request. Taking into account the nature of the Personal Information and purposes of processing the Personal Information, you have the right to request that we correct inaccurate Personal Information about you, if applicable.

f. Right to Limit Use and Disclosure of Sensitive Personal Information

If we process Sensitive Personal Information, we will only do so for the purposes specifically authorized by California law and in a manner that is necessary and proportionate for those purposes. As such, we do not perform any processing for which a Right to Limit request is available.

g. Submitting Requests

You can submit your request by visiting our **“Your Privacy Choices”** link in the footer of our websites or by toll-free phone at 1-866-675-7529 and leave a detailed message your first and last name, date of birth, email address and zip code, along with instructions for the correction. Please provide the information associated with your account or that you use to transact with Alterra Mountain Company. You must provide all required information to submit a request. Only complete requests received by Alterra Mountain Company’s Privacy office that include all required information and that are matched with information in our records will be processed. For your safety and security, we may ask you for more information where required to verify your identity. In the event that we refuse a request, we will provide you a reason as to why.

h. Verifying Requests

To ensure the protection of your Personal Information, we must verify that the individual submitting a request to know, request to delete, or request to correct is the consumer to whom the request relates prior to processing the request. To verify a California consumer’s identity, we may request up to four pieces (including your name, date of birth, email address and/or zip code) of Personal Information about you when you make a request to compare against our records. Please provide the information associated with your account or that you use to transact with Alterra Mountain Company. We may also request that you sign a declaration under the penalty of perjury from the consumer whose Personal Information is the subject of the request.

Making a verifiable consumer request does not require you to create an account with us.

We will only use Personal Information provided in your request to verify your identity and will delete any information you provide after processing the request. We reserve the right to take additional steps as necessary to verify the identity of California consumers where we have reason to believe a request is fraudulent.

i. Authorized Agents

You may choose a person or a business registered with the California Secretary of State that you authorize to act on your behalf to submit your requests (“**Authorized Agent**”). If you choose to use an Authorized Agent, we require that you provide the Authorized Agent with written permission to allow them to submit your request and that you verify your identity directly with us. Failure to do so may result in Alterra Mountain Company denying your request.

We reserve our right not to respond to requests sent more than once in a calendar year, or requests submitted to an address other than the one set out in this policy.

**_(b) Colorado, Connecticut, and Virginia Customers_**

Colorado, Connecticut, Utah and Virginia residents have certain rights with respect to their data. These rights are established through the Colorado Privacy Act (“**CPA**”), the Connecticut Data Privacy Act (“**CTDPA**”), the Utah Consumer Privacy Act (“**UCPA**”), and the Virginia Consumer Data Protection Act (“**VCDPA**”). The chart below explains these rights and lists the states whose residents may exercise those rights. To exercise any of the following rights listed in the chart below, please click on the “Your Privacy Choices” link in the footer of our websites or call 1-866-675-7529 and follow the instructions in the “Your Privacy Options” section above.

| Consumer Right | Explanation | Applies to Residents of: |
| --- | --- | --- |
| * * * | * * * | * * * |
| Right to Know/Access | You have the right to confirm whether we are processing your personal data, and the right to access that data. | Colorado, Connecticut, Utah, Virginia |
| * * * | * * * | * * * |
| Right of Correction | You have the right to correct inaccuracies in your personal data, taking into account the nature of the personal data and the purposes of the processing of the personal data. | Colorado, Connecticut, Utah, Virginia |
| * * * | * * * | * * * |
| Right of Deletion | You have the right to delete, subject to certain exceptions, your personal data provided by you or obtained about you. \*Note: If you are a Utah resident, this only applies to personal data you have provided directly to us. | Colorado, Connecticut, Utah\*, Virginia |
| * * * | * * * | * * * |
| Right of Portability | Up to two times per calendar year, you have the right to obtain your personal data in a portable and—to the extent technically feasible—readily usable format that allows you to transmit the data to another entity without hindrance. This right is exercised in conjunction with the Right to Know/Access. To exercise the Right of Portability, please follow the instructions to exercise your Right to Know/Access as described in the “Your Privacy Choices” page. \*Note: If you are a Utah resident, this only applies to processing carried out by automated means. | Colorado, Connecticut, Utah\*, Virginia |
| * * * | * * * | * * * |
| Right to Opt-out: Colorado, Connecticut, and Virginia | You have the right to opt-out of the processing of your personal data for the purposes of: (1) Targeted advertising; (2) The sale of personal data; and/or (3) Profiling in furtherance of decisions that produce legal or similarly significant effects concerning you. To opt-out, please visit our “Your Privacy Choices” page. | Colorado, Connecticut, Virginia |
| * * * | * * * | * * * |
| Right to Opt-out: Utah | You have the right to opt-out of the sale of personal data or targeted advertising. To opt-out, please visit our “Your Privacy Choices” page. | Utah |

**Sensitive Data**

Sensitive Data as defined in the CPA, CTDPA, UCPA, and VCDPA includes precise geolocation information, an individual’s racial or ethnic origin, mental or physical health condition or diagnosis, sexual orientation, and citizenship status. We will not collect this information from Connecticut and Virginia residents without first obtaining consent. We will not collect this information from Utah residents without first presenting them with clear notice and an opportunity to opt out of the processing\[A8\] . We will not collect this information from Colorado residents without first obtaining consent . Please note the collection and processing of Sensitive Data (as defined in certain state statutes) is necessary to administer the Services.

**Exercising Your Rights**

If you are a Colorado, Connecticut, Utah, or Virginia resident and wish to exercise one of the above rights and it applies to you, please visit our **“Your Privacy Choices”** link in the footer of our websites. If necessary, we may request additional information reasonably necessary to authenticate you and your request.

In certain circumstances, you may make a request on behalf of another such as if you are an authorized agent or the parent or guardian of a child on behalf of whom you wish to exercise their rights.

We will respond to these consumer requests, if applicable, within 45 days of receipt of the request and without undue delay. If we need to extend this period, we will notify you of the delay and explain the reasonably necessary justifications for our delay.

We will provide responses to your requests free of charge unless certain exclusions apply, depending on the state in which you reside. We may charge a fee in:

* Colorado, Connecticut and Utah, if you make more than one request in a twelve-month period; and
* Connecticut and Virginia, if the request is manifestly unfounded or excessive, or repetitive in nature.

**_Appealing a Rights Request Decision_**

If you are a resident of Colorado, Connecticut, or Virginia, and we deny or fail to take action on your request to exercise your applicable consumer privacy rights, you may appeal our decision. To do this, you may email us at [yourprivacy@alterramtnco.com](mailto:yourprivacy@alterramtnco.com). In the email appeal, please specify the right(s) you requested to exercise and the date you made such a request.

We will inform you in writing within 45 days of any action taken or not taken in response to the appeal. We will also provide a written explanation of the reasons for our decisions regarding your request(s).

_(c) European Union, Switzerland and United Kingdom Customers_

This section of our Privacy Policy is applicable to persons located in the European Union (“**EU**”), an European Economic Area member state (“**EEA**”), United Kingdom (“**UK**”), or Switzerland as well as to persons whose Personal Information is processed in or transferred from the EU, EEA, UK, or Switzerland. You are entitled under the EU General Data Protection Regulation and UK General Data Protection Regulation (collectively, the “**GDPR**”), to the information in this section of our Privacy Policy.

**Your** **Rights**

You are entitled by law to access, correct, amend, or delete Personal Information about you that we hold. A summary listing these rights appears below. Please note that these rights are not absolute and certain exemptions may apply to specific requests that you may submit to us.

To exercise these rights, please visit our **“Your Privacy Choices”** link in the footer of our websites or by toll-free phone at 1-866-675-7529 and leave a detailed message your first and last name, date of birth, email address and zip code, along with instructions for the correction. Please provide the information associated with your account or that you use to transact with Alterra Mountain Company. You must provide all required information to submit a request. Only complete requests received by Alterra Mountain Company’s Privacy office that include all required information and that are matched with information in our records will be processed. For your safety and security, we may ask you for more information where required to verify your identity. In the event that we refuse a request, we will provide you a reason as to why.

_Asking us to access your Personal Information_

You have the right to obtain from us confirmation as to whether or not we are processing Personal Information about you, and if so, the right to be provided with the information contained in this Policy. You also have the right to ask us for copies of your Personal Information. When making a request, please provide an accurate description of the Personal Information to which you want access. Where requests are repetitive or manifestly unfounded or excessive, we may charge a reasonable fee based on administrative cost.

_Asking us to rectify your Personal Information_

You have the right to ask us to rectify information you think is inaccurate. You also have the right to ask us to complete information you think is incomplete.

_Asking us to delete your Personal Information_

You have the right to ask us to erase your Personal Information if:

* We no longer need it for the purposes for which we collected it;
* We have been using it with no valid legal basis;
* We are obligated to erase it to comply with a legal obligation to which we are subject;
* We need your consent to use the information and you withdraw consent; or
* You object to us processing your Personal Information where our legal basis for doing so is our legitimate interests and there are no overriding legitimate grounds for the processing.

However, this right is not absolute. Even if you make a request for deletion, we may need to retain certain information for legal or administrative purposes, such as record keeping, maintenance of opt-out requirements, defending or making legal claims, or detecting fraudulent activities. We will retain information in accordance with the “How Long We Keep Your Personal Information” section above.

If you do exercise a valid right to have your Personal Information deleted, please keep in mind that deletion by third parties to whom the information has been provided might not be immediate and that the deleted information may persist in backup copies for a reasonable period (but will not be available to others).

_Asking us to restrict our use of your Personal Information_

You have the right to ask us to place a restriction on our use of your Personal Information if one of the following applies to you:

* You contest the accuracy of the information that we hold about you, while we verify its accuracy;
* We have used your information unlawfully, but you request us to restrict its use instead of erasing it;
* We no longer need the information for the purpose for which we collected it, but you need it to deal with a legal claim; or
* You have objected to us using your information, while we check whether our legitimate grounds override your right to object.

_The right to transfer your Personal Information to another service provider_

You have the right to ask that we transfer the Personal Information you gave us from one organization to another, or give it to you (_i.e.,_ data portability). This applies to Personal Information we are processing to service a contract with you and to Personal Information we are processing based on your consent.

_The right to withdraw consent_

If we obtain your written consent to collect and process your Personal Information, you can subsequently withdraw such consent as to any further processing of such information.

_The right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority_

If you believe your rights under the GDPR have been violated, the GDPR gives you the right to file a complaint with your supervisory authority. A list of supervisory authorities is available here: [EEA and EU Data Protection Authorities (DPAs)](https://ec.europa.eu/newsroom/article29/item-detail.cfm?item_id=612080); Swiss Federal Data Protection and Information Commissioner (FDPIC); [UK Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO)](https://ico.org.uk/make-a-complaint/).

_Rights related to automated decision-making_

To the extent that we engage in decision-making based solely on automated processing, including profiling, which produces legal effects concerning you or which significantly affects you, you have the right not to be subject to such decision-making.

_Right to object to processing_

You have the right to object to the processing of your Personal Information that is based on legitimate interests or your consent (rather than when the reason for using it is to perform an obligation due to you under a contract with us). If you make such an objection, we will cease to process the Personal Information unless we can demonstrate compelling legitimate grounds for the processing which override your interests, rights and freedoms, or we can demonstrate the processing is for the establishment, exercise, or defense of legal claims. You can object to the processing of your Personal Information by contacting us using the information in the “Contact Us” section below.

**Legal Bases for Processing Your Personal Information**

Alterra Mountain Company collects your Personal Information to provide our products and Services to you; otherwise, we may not be able to process the transactions you request. We will only process your Personal Information when we have a lawful basis for doing so. If you are in a country in the EU, EEA, UK, or Switzerland, you are entitled to an explanation of the legal bases we rely on to process your Personal Information. The legal basis for collecting and using the Personal Information described above will depend on the Personal Information concerned and the specific context in which we collect it, which is discussed below.

* **Consent.** We may process your personal information based on your consent such as when you purchase a service or ask us to send you certain kinds of marketing communications. You have the right to withdraw your consent at any time without affecting the lawfulness of the processing based on consent before its withdrawal.
    * **Children's** **Consent.** We do not knowingly process data of EU, EEA, UK, or Swiss residents under the age of 16 without reasonably verified parental consent.

* **Our Legitimate Interests.** We may process your personal information if doing so is necessary for our legitimate interests relating to our business purposes arising from your relationship with us, and your rights as an individual do not override those legitimate interests. For example, our legitimate interests include but are not limited to when we process your personal information to carry out fraud prevention activities and activities to increase network and information security, identify usage trends, determine the effectiveness of promotional campaigns, expand our business activities and improve our services and the content and functionality of our Services. Our legitimate interests also include providing you with the products and services you request, view, engage with, or purchase and communicating with you regarding your account or transactions with us.

* **To** **Perform a Contract.** We may process your personal information to administer and fulfill contractual obligations to you. We will also collect and process your personal information as necessary for the performance of a contract to which you are a party.

* **To Enable Us to Comply with a Legal Obligation.** We may process your personal information to comply with legal obligations to which we are subject. This may include any requirement to produce audited accounts, any legal obligation to share information with law enforcement agencies, public or governmental authorities, and to comply with legal process.

* **Necessary for the Exercise or Defense of Legal Claims.** If you bring a claim against us or we bring a claim against you, we may process your personal information in relation to that claim.

Depending on the situation, we may be the controller or the processor for personal information collected from residents of the EU, EEA, UK or Switzerland. If you have any questions about or need further information concerning the legal basis on which we collect and use your personal information for any specific processing activity, please contact us using the information in the “Contact Us” section below.

**Cross-Border Transfers of Personal Information**

Our Services are operated in the United States. Personal information about you provide while in the EU, an EEA member state, the UK, or Switzerland may be transferred to the United States. The United States does not have an adequacy decision or adequacy regulation. The GDPR permits such transfers when necessary for the performance of a contract between you and us, if we obtain your explicit consent to such transfer, or if it is in our legitimate interest to transfer the personal information. The laws in the United States may not be as protective as the GDPR or the laws of other jurisdictions where you may be located. If we transfer personal information from the EU, EEA, UK, or Switzerland, or another country with cross-border transfer obligations, we will provide an appropriate safeguard, such as using standard contractual clauses.

To obtain a copy of the safeguard(s), please contact us using the information provided in the “Contact Us” section below.

**12\. THIRD PARTY LINKS**

We may include links to third party sites on our websites. When we provide links, we do so only as a convenience and we are not responsible for any content of any third-party websites or any links contained within. When you click on those third-party links, you leave our website. This Policy does not apply to third party sites or any information that you provide on those sites. We are not responsible and assume no responsibility for personal information collected, stored, or used by any third party as a result of you visiting third-party websites. We also advise that you carefully read the privacy notice of any third-party websites you choose to visit.

**13\. SUBJECT TO CHANGE**

This Policy is subject to change and may be supplemented or modified at any time. You should check this site regularly to stay up to date about changes to this Policy. If material changes are made, we will notify you by placing a notice on our website [https://www.alterramtnco.com/privacy-policy.](https://www.alterramtnco.com/privacy-policy) Your continued use of our Services constitutes acceptance of the most current version of this Policy.

**14\. CONTACT US**

If you have any questions regarding our privacy practices, you may contact us at:

Mail:

Alterra Mountain Company

3501 Wazee Street, Suite 400

Denver, CO 80216

Attention: Chief Privacy Officer

Phone: 1-866-675-7529 (North American Toll-Free)

Email: [yourprivacy@alterramtnco.com](mailto:yourprivacy@alterramtnco.com)

Politique de vie privée
-----------------------

**ENTRÉE EN VIGUEUR: janvier 2004  
MISE À JOUR: février 2024**

Alterra Mountain Company s’engage à respecter la confidentialité de ses clients, des détenteurs de forfaits et des propriétaires (« vous », « votre », et « vos »). La politique de confidentialité de l’entreprise Alterra Mountain Company (la « Politique ») s’applique aux renseignements personnels que l’entreprise Alterra Mountain Company recueille en ligne, en personne, par l’entremise de ses centres d’appels ou d’une quelconque autre manière.

Les « Renseignements personnels » désignent toutes les informations considérées comme étant des informations à caractère personnel, des données à caractère personnel, des informations personnelles identifiables ou autres termes similaires employés dans les lois et les règlements en matière de confidentialité et de sécurité des données. Les Renseignements personnels ne comprennent pas les données qui sont exclues ou exemptées desdites lois et desdits règlements, telles que les informations agrégées, anonymisées ou dépersonnalisées qui ne peuvent pas être associées à une personne en particulier.

« Alterra Mountain Company », « nous », « notre » ou « nos » désigne Alterra Mountain Company et ses filiales, y compris ses stations de montagne, Ikon Pass, Ski Butlers et certaines de leurs sociétés affiliées. Nous sommes présents à l’échelle internationale et possédons des bureaux et des installations dans plusieurs juridictions aux États-Unis et au Canada. Sauf dans les cas où la politique de confidentialité d’une société affiliée, d’un tiers ou d’un partenaire s’applique, toutes nos activités commerciales sont soumises à la présente Politique. Pour obtenir la liste complète des stations et des actifs d’Alterra Mountain Company, veuillez consulter le site alterramtnco.com.

La présente Politique ne s’applique pas aux informations concernant les employés d’Alterra Mountain Company ou aux informations qui ne sont pas des Renseignements personnels. Les employés d’Alterra Mountain Company doivent consulter la Politique de confidentialité du personnel pour obtenir des informations sur la protection de la vie privée sur le lieu de travail.

**POLICY CONTENT**

1. [LES RENSEIGNEMENTS PERSONNELS QUE NOUS RECUEILLONS ET COMMENT ILS SONT UTILISÉS](#les-renseignements-personnels)
    1. [Nous recueillons vos Renseignements personnels lorsque vous achetez un produit ou un service, effectuez une réservation, visitez nos stations ou vous inscrivez à un programme.](#a-les-renseignements-personnels)
    2. [Nous recueillons vos Renseignements personnels lorsque vous visitez nos stations et nos sites Web et lorsque vous utilisez nos produits de type forfait, passe de fréquence et billet, et autres services.](#b-les-renseignements-personnels)
    3. [Nous recueillons vos Renseignements personnels lorsque vous téléchargez et utilisez nos applications Web ou mobiles (les « Applications »).](#c-les-renseignements-personnels)
    4. [Nous recueillons vos Renseignements personnels lorsque vous soumettez une demande, participez à une session de clavardage, répondez à une enquête client ou transmettez des commentaires.](#d-les-renseignements-personnels)
    5. [Nous recueillons vos Renseignements personnels lorsque vous participez à une initiative de marketing ou créez un compte en ligne.](#e-les-renseignements-personnels)
    6. [Nous recueillons vos Renseignements personnels lorsque vous appelez nos centres d’appels ou lorsque nous vous appelons.](#f-les-renseignements-personnels)
    7. [Nous recueillons vos Renseignements personnels auprès de prestataires de services et d’autres tiers.](#g-les-renseignements-personnels)
2. [NOTRE RECUEIL D’INFORMATIONS PAR LE BIAIS DE TÉMOINS ET D’AUTRES TECHNOLOGIES DE SUIVI.](#recueil-informations)
3. [À QUELLE OCCASION POUVONS-NOUS COMBINER VOS INFORMATIONS PERSONNELLES?](#occasion-pouvons-nous-combiner)
4. [DANS QUELS CAS COMMUNIQUONS-NOUS VOS RENSEIGNEMENTS PERSONNELS?](#quels-cas-communiquons-nous)
5. [VOTRE CONSENTEMENT](#votre-consentement)
6. [COMMENT GÉRER VOS PRÉFÉRENCES EN MATIÈRE DE MARKETING](#comment-gerer-vos-preferences)
7. [CONFIDENTIALITÉ DES ENFANTS](#enfants)
8. [DURÉE DE CONSERVATION DE VOS RENSEIGNEMENTS PERSONNELS](#duree-de-conservation)
9. [COMMENT NOUS PROTÉGEONS VOS DONNÉES](#nous-protegeons-vos-donnees)
10. [OÙ CONSERVONS-NOUS VOS RENSEIGNEMENTS PERSONNELS?](#conservons-nous-renseignements-personnels)
11. [VOS OPTIONS ET VOS DROITS EN MATIÈRE DE CONFIDENTIALITÉ](#options-et-vos-droits-en-matiere-de-confidentialite)
    1. [_Clients situés en Californie_](#clients-californie)
    2. _[Clients situés dans le Colorado, dans le Connecticut, dans l’Utah et en Virginie](#clients-colorado-connecticut-utah-virginie)_
    3. [_Clients situés dans l’Union européenne, en Suisse et au Royaume-Uni_](#clients-union-europeenne-suisse-royaume-uni)
12. [LIENS TIERS](#liens-tiers)
13. [MODIFICATION DE LA POLITIQUE](#modification-politique)
14. [NOUS CONTACTER](#nous-contacter)

**1\. LES RENSEIGNEMENTS PERSONNELS QUE NOUS RECUEILLONS ET COMMENT ILS SONT UTILISÉS**

Alterra Mountain Company recueille des Renseignements personnels dans le cadre de nos activités en station de montagne, d’accueil en station et immobilières, notamment par le biais de nos Applications, de nos sites Web, et lorsque vous interagissez avec nous d’une quelconque autre manière (collectivement, les « **Services** »). Nous utilisons ces informations pour vous fournir le meilleur service possible, faciliter vos achats de produits ou de services, et pour répondre à nos besoins commerciaux raisonnables.

_(a) Nous recueillons vos Renseignements personnels lorsque vous achetez un produit ou un service, effectuez une réservation, visitez nos stations ou vous inscrivez à un programme._

Lorsque vous achetez un produit ou un service, que vous faites une réservation, que vous visitez nos stations ou que vous vous inscrivez à un programme, nous recueillons des Renseignements personnels afin de traiter la transaction et de gérer l’achat, la réservation ou le programme en question et, en fonction de vos préférences en matière de marketing, pour vous envoyer des communications personnalisées sur les produits et services qui, selon nous, pourraient vous intéresser. Nous pouvons également vous envoyer des communications concernant votre achat, votre réservation ou votre participation à un programme. À titre d’exemple, si vous effectuez une réservation dans l’une de nos stations, il est possible que vous receviez de notre part des informations sur les activités, les évènements ou les offres prévus dans ce centre au moment de votre visite.

Les Renseignements personnels que nous pouvons recueillir et utiliser à ces fins comprennent :

* votre nom et vos coordonnées pour vous identifier et communiquer avec vous;
* des informations sur votre carte de paiement pour le traitement des transactions;
* votre âge et/ou votre date de naissance afin de garantir une tarification appropriée des produits et d’en savoir plus sur les personnes qui profitent de nos produits et de nos services;
* votre genre, pour vérifier votre identité, pour fournir des services appropriés, notamment pour la location d’équipements, et pour en savoir plus sur les personnes qui profitent de nos produits et de nos services;
* des informations concernant vos caractéristiques physiques, lorsque ces informations sont nécessaires, en rapport avec le produit, le service, le programme ou l’activité que vous avez demandé (par exemple, nous pouvons avoir besoin de votre taille, de votre poids et de votre pointure de chaussures pour vous fournir un équipement de location approprié);
* vos informations médicales ou de santé (telles que des allergies ou des problèmes médicaux dont nous devons être informés si vous participez à des leçons ou à d’autres programmes, ou si vous avez des restrictions alimentaires);
* une photographie de votre visage pour vous identifier en tant que titulaire d’un forfait;
* votre statut de parent ou de tuteur d’un participant mineur, le cas échéant;
* vos préférences en matière de ski ou d’expérience (à titre d’exemple, le type de chambre d’hôtel que vous préférez, si vous êtes un skieur ou un planchiste) pour en savoir plus sur les personnes qui profitent de nos produits et de nos services;
* des renseignements d’ordre démographique, notamment votre origine ethnique, pour en savoir plus sur les personnes qui profitent de nos produits et de nos services;
* des informations sur votre revenu et votre éducation, pour en savoir plus sur les personnes qui profitent de nos produits et de nos services;
* les numéros de sécurité sociale ou d’assurance sociale ou tout autre numéro d’identification fiscale des propriétaires qui participent à notre programme de gestion locative afin que nous puissions procéder au paiement de vos revenus locatifs;
* votre localisation géographique pour localiser les participants à l’école de ski ou d’autres clients qui ont choisi d’utiliser la technologie de suivi en montagne pendant qu’ils se trouvent dans nos stations, y compris nos applications qui offrent le suivi en montagne; et
* l’historique de vos achats et de vos transactions pour gérer vos achats et vos réservations et pour en savoir plus sur la manière dont vous interagissez avec nos produits et nos services ou avec les produits et les services des prestataires et partenaires du secteur.

Il peut arriver que vous nous communiquiez des Renseignements personnels concernant un membre de votre famille ou une autre personne. En nous fournissant des Renseignements personnels qui concernent une personne autre que vous-même, vous déclarez avoir le consentement de ladite personne pour nous fournir ses Renseignements personnels aux fins décrites dans la présente Politique.

Nous pouvons utiliser lesdits Renseignements personnels à des fins de publicité et de vente ciblées, et nous pouvons les vendre ou les partager avec des Partenaires du secteur et des Stations acceptant nos forfaits (définis ci-dessous).

_(b) Nous recueillons vos Renseignements personnels lorsque vous visitez nos stations et nos sites Web et lorsque vous utilisez nos produits de type forfait, passe de fréquence et billet, et autres services._

Lorsque vous achetez ou utilisez nos produits de type forfait, passe de fréquence et billet, nous pouvons recueillir des informations concernant votre localisation géographique, vos activités, vos passages aux portiques et vos achats lorsque vous êtes dans les stations d’Alterra Mountain Company. Nos forfaits et nos billets utilisent soit un lecteur portatif soit la technologie RFID (identification par radiofréquence). Cette technologie nous permet de recueillir des informations limitées concernant votre visite dans une station, y compris les passages aux portiques et les remontées mécaniques que vous utilisez, et selon que votre carte de paiement est liée ou non à votre forfait, d’autres transactions commerciales que vous effectuez dans nos magasins ou restaurants. Nous utilisons ces informations pour comprendre l’utilisation que font nos clients de nos stations et pour connaître vos préférences personnelles, ce qui nous aide à améliorer nos produits et nos services.

En fonction de vos préférences en matière de marketing, nous pouvons également utiliser vos Renseignements personnels pour vous envoyer des offres, des invitations ou des promotions concernant nos stations, nos produits, nos services ou nos programmes qui, selon nous, pourraient vous intéresser. À titre d’exemple, nous pouvons utiliser des informations extraites de l’historique de vos achats dans nos stations ou lors de vos interactions avec nos sites Web pour vous envoyer des offres et des promotions personnalisées ou spéciales.

Certains de nos forfaits vous donnent accès à des stations de ski qui ne sont pas détenues ou exploitées par Alterra Mountain Company (chacune dénommée « **Station acceptant nos forfaits** »). Lorsque vous utilisez votre forfait dans une Station acceptant nos forfaits, ladite station numérisera, ou enregistrera d’une quelconque autre manière, votre présence à l’aide de la technologie RFID (identification par radiofréquence), de lecteurs portatifs ou de toute autre méthode qui permet à la Station acceptant nos forfaits et à nous-mêmes d’enregistrer l’utilisation que vous faites du forfait. Nous pouvons également partager vos Renseignements personnels avec une Station acceptant nos forfaits afin de gérer votre forfait, de mieux comprendre l’utilisation que vous faites de vos forfaits et d’appréhender la manière dont nous pouvons améliorer l’expérience des clients.

Plusieurs de nos stations utilisent la technologie de suivi GPS dans le cadre de leurs programmes avec des écoles de ski et de planche afin de suivre et de localiser les élèves sur la montagne. La technologie de suivi GPS est détenue et exploitée par un prestataire de services tiers qui peut recevoir certains Renseignements personnels, notamment le nom et l’adresse électronique, pour fournir le service de suivi et faciliter l’utilisation de son site Web sur lequel vous et/ou les membres de votre famille pouvez suivre votre journée d’apprentissage sur la montagne.

Dans certaines de nos stations, il se peut que nous utilisions des webcaméras et des systèmes de vidéosurveillance pour assurer la sécurité de nos clients, de nos employés et de nos biens, et pour en savoir plus sur le nombre de clients qui visitent nos stations et à quel moment, pour prendre des décisions d’ordre opérationnel, notamment en matière de gestion des effectifs et des horaires d’ouverture. Nous conserverons les enregistrements de vidéosurveillance aussi longtemps que cela sera raisonnablement nécessaire à ces fins. Nos stations peuvent également utiliser des webcaméras en direct dans les zones publiques extérieures, que ce soit en montagne ou dans la zone du village de base. Ces webcaméras avec transmission en direct peuvent être consultées par n’importe qui disposant d’une connexion Internet et, dans certains cas, votre image ou vos traits physiques identifiables peuvent apparaître de manière temporaire dans les enregistrements des webcaméras.

Si vous louez ou essayez du matériel qui dépend de nos stations ou de nos activités, nous recueillerons vos Renseignements personnels, y compris vos caractéristiques physiques et vos préférences en matière de ski, afin de vous proposer un matériel adapté et de vous le louer.

Nous pouvons utiliser lesdits Renseignements personnels à des fins de publicité et de vente ciblées, et nous pouvons les vendre ou les partager avec des Partenaires du secteur et des Stations acceptant nos forfaits.

_(c) Nous recueillons vos Renseignements personnels lorsque vous téléchargez et utilisez nos applications Web ou mobiles (les « Applications »)._

Certaines de nos stations et certains de nos produits disposent d’Applications que vous pouvez télécharger sur votre appareil mobile. Le téléchargement, l’installation et l’utilisation de nos Applications vous permettront d’accéder facilement aux formidables expériences que nos stations ont à offrir, y compris la possibilité de créer un profil et d’acheter des forfaits, des billets de remontée, de suivre et de partager vos performances, de créer des groupes sociaux avec lesquels vous pouvez partager des informations (notamment des données de géolocalisation), de gagner des badges pour célébrer vos accomplissements, de communiquer par clavardage avec d’autres personnes de vos groupes sociaux, de participer à des concours et à des évènements, d’accéder à des informations sur l’orientation en montagne, la météo et les remontées mécaniques, et de recevoir des notifications au sein des Applications (collectivement, les « **Services des applications** »). Si vous accédez à nos Applications, nous pouvons être en mesure de recueillir vos Renseignements personnels en fonction de vos paramètres, y compris votre localisation géographique exacte, les informations relatives à votre activité (y compris votre vitesse), l’historique de vos achats et votre interaction avec les Applications. Nos étiquettes nutritionnelles de confidentialité et nos divulgations de sécurité des données sont accessibles sur l’App Store ou sur Google Play. Nous pouvons également associer les informations recueillies par le biais de votre utilisation des Applications à votre profil client, y compris vos forfaits et les données de lecture des forfaits.

Les Applications recueillent automatiquement des informations détaillées de localisation et de navigation, sous forme de signaux GPS provenant de l’appareil mobile sur lequel vous avez installé et activé les Applications (les « **Informations de localisation des applications** »). Chaque fois que vous ouvrez, utilisez ou interagissez avec les Services des applications, nous utilisons vos Informations de localisation des applications (par exemple, latitude et longitude) pour adapter l’expérience offerte par les Services des applications à votre emplacement actuel. Nous utilisons également vos Informations de localisation des applications pour fournir certains Services des applications, notamment pour vous envoyer des notifications concernant des amis, des évènements ou d’autres informations pertinentes qui se trouvent à proximité. Si vous avez activé la « localisation en arrière-plan », les Applications peuvent, de temps à autre, nous transmettre la localisation de votre appareil, même si vous n’interagissez pas directement avec les Applications. Nous pouvons avoir recours à diverses technologies pour déterminer les Informations de localisation des applications, telles que les services de localisation du système d’exploitation ou du navigateur applicable, les données GPS, Bluetooth, i-Beacon, RFID, les données des capteurs de vos appareils, les points d’accès Wi-Fi et les tours de téléphonie cellulaire à proximité, ainsi que d’autres technologies pour déterminer la localisation approximative de vos appareils mobiles.

Les Applications peuvent également partager vos Informations de localisation des applications sur une carte ou en communiquant votre distance et votre trajectoire générale à d’autres utilisateurs. Ne partagez vos Informations de localisation des applications qu’avec les personnes en qui vous avez confiance. Vous comprenez que la nature des services de localisation est telle que les Informations de localisation des applications sont disponibles pour vous et d’autres utilisateurs, et que nous ne pouvons pas contrôler ce que vous ou d’autres utilisateurs, qui recevez ces informations lors de l’utilisation des Applications ou des Services des applications, en ferez.

Si vous ne souhaitez pas que les Applications suivent vos Informations de localisation des applications, vous devez désactiver la fonction de suivi des Informations de localisation des applications dans le menu des paramètres des Applications. Si vous désactivez la fonction de suivi des Informations de localisation des applications, certaines fonctions des Applications et certains des Services des applications ne pourront pas être fournis sans l’utilisation de cette technologie standard. À titre d’exemple, les Services des applications utilisent vos informations de localisation et d’itinéraire pour créer un historique détaillé des trajets que vous effectuez lorsque vous utilisez les Applications et les Services des applications. Les Applications utilisent cet historique pour vous offrir les Services des applications, pour améliorer la qualité des Services des applications qu’elles offrent à vous comme à tous leurs utilisateurs et pour améliorer la précision de leurs données de cartographie et de navigation.

Vous pouvez être en mesure de prendre part à certaines activités au sein de nos Services des applications qui vous permettent de communiquer ou de partager des informations non seulement avec nous, mais aussi avec d’autres utilisateurs. Il s’agit notamment des activités suivantes :

* envoyer des messages ou des contenus privés ou de groupe à d’autres utilisateurs,
* clavarder avec d’autres utilisateurs,
* partager des mesures de performance, telles que le nombre total de jours de ski, la distance parcourue en ski et le nombre de remontées prises,
* partager votre niveau de compétence, votre montagne d’origine et/ou vos préférences personnelles,
* partager des photos ou des dessins avec d’autres utilisateurs

Nous enregistrons et stockons les archives de ces données sur des serveurs pour fournir ces fonctionnalités ainsi que pour protéger nos droits et notre propriété en relation avec nos Services des applications, et vous reconnaissez et acceptez par les présentes notre stockage de ces données.

Nous pouvons utiliser lesdits Renseignements personnels à des fins de publicité et de vente ciblées, et nous pouvons les vendre ou les partager avec des Partenaires du secteur et des Stations acceptant nos forfaits.

_(d) Nous recueillons vos Renseignements personnels lorsque vous soumettez une demande, participez à une session de clavardage, répondez à une enquête client ou transmettez des commentaires._

Nous pouvons recueillir votre nom, vos coordonnées et vos commentaires ou questions lorsque vous soumettez une demande de renseignements ou un commentaire, participez à une session de clavardage ou nous transmettez vos retours d’expérience sur nos activités. Si vous utilisez la fonction robot conversationnel sur nos sites Web, nous enregistrerons la conversation. Veuillez noter que le robot conversationnel est un programme automatisé et non une personne réelle, et que les informations relatives à vos communications peuvent être partagées avec notre prestataire de services.

Nous pouvons également recueillir des informations relatives à votre expérience dans l’une de nos stations ou à l’utilisation de nos produits ou de nos services dans le cadre d’une enquête de satisfaction des clients. Ces enquêtes peuvent inclure des questions facultatives concernant votre revenu, votre niveau d’éducation, votre race/origine ethnique ou votre sexe qui, si vous y répondez, nous aident à en savoir plus sur nos clients et sur la manière dont nous pouvons améliorer notre engagement commercial et public ainsi que la diversité, l’équité et l’inclusion dans les sports de neige. Nous pouvons utiliser ces informations pour répondre à vos questions et pour améliorer nos activités, nos produits, nos services et nos programmes.

_(e) Nous recueillons vos Renseignements personnels lorsque vous participez à une initiative de marketing ou créez un compte en ligne._

Si vous choisissez de créer un profil de compte en ligne, nous pouvons recueillir votre nom, vos coordonnées, votre âge, votre sexe, votre date de naissance, votre image personnelle, votre nom d’utilisateur et votre mot de passe, ainsi que d’autres informations que vous choisissez de fournir (telles que vos préférences en matière de sports de neige).

Nous pouvons également recueillir votre nom, vos coordonnées, votre âge et/ou votre date de naissance si vous décidez de participer à une initiative de marketing telle qu’un concours, un tirage au sort ou une autre activité promotionnelle. Dans certains cas, nous pouvons également vous poser des questions spécifiques sur vos préférences ou vous demander votre avis sur nos activités, nos produits, nos services et nos programmes. Nous utilisons ces informations pour gérer la promotion, y compris pour contacter et annoncer les gagnants (le cas échéant), pour améliorer notre activité, nos produits, nos services et nos programmes, et pour des initiatives de marketing, telles que des offres ou des promotions relatives à nos stations, à nos produits, à nos services ou à nos programmes qui, selon nous, pourraient vous intéresser, en fonction de vos préférences en matière de marketing.

_(f) Nous recueillons vos Renseignements personnels lorsque vous appelez nos centres d’appels ou lorsque nous vous appelons._

Nous pouvons enregistrer les appels entrants et sortants de nos centres d’appels afin de tenir des registres précis et à des fins d’assurance qualité et de formation. Nous conserverons les enregistrements d’appels aussi longtemps que cela sera raisonnablement nécessaire à ces fins.

_(g) Nous recueillons vos Renseignements personnels auprès de prestataires de services et d’autres tiers._

Si vous êtes un résident des États-Unis, nous pouvons également compléter les Renseignements personnels que vous nous fournissez par des informations que nous obtenons auprès de tiers.

**2\. NOTRE RECUEIL D’INFORMATIONS PAR LE BIAIS DE TÉMOINS ET D’AUTRES TECHNOLOGIES DE SUIVI.**

Lorsque vous visitez l’un de nos sites Web ou utilisez l’une de nos Applications, votre navigateur nous envoie certaines informations en fonction du navigateur que vous utilisez et de vos paramètres de confidentialité et de sécurité. Ces informations peuvent inclure votre adresse IP, le nom et la version de votre système d’exploitation, le nom et la version de votre navigateur, d’autres données techniques, le fait que vous avez accédé à notre site Web depuis un ordinateur ou un appareil mobile, le moment où vous ouvrez les courriels que nous vous envoyons, la date, l’heure et la durée de votre visite, et les données de géolocalisation. Nous pouvons également utiliser des outils de relecture de session sur nos sites Web et dans nos Applications pour enregistrer vos interactions avec les sites Web et les Applications, comme la façon dont vous vous déplacez sur les sites Web et les Applications et la façon dont vous abordez nos formulaires Web. Les données du navigateur et les outils de relecture de session facilitent la gestion du système, le transfert de trafic et l’audit. Ils nous aident également à mieux comprendre qui sont nos clients, comment ils utilisent nos produits et nos services, et ce que nous pouvons faire pour améliorer l’expérience utilisateur. Nous pouvons utiliser ces informations pour vous offrir des produits et des services et pour créer des statistiques globales. Cela nous aide à améliorer votre expérience en ligne et dans nos stations.

Nous utilisons également des « témoins », y compris des pixels, pour personnaliser votre expérience utilisateur du site Web en adaptant le contenu en ligne à vos habitudes de navigation. Les témoins sont des données infimes stockées sur votre disque dur, qui nous envoient des informations sur vos habitudes de navigation en ligne, notamment l’historique de connexion et de navigation, l’exposition aux boutons et les préférences personnelles. Les témoins nous indiquent également sous quel compte un utilisateur est connecté à l’un de nos sites Web et ces informations nous aident à protéger vos renseignements en veillant à ce que vos préférences personnelles ne soient affichées que lorsque vous êtes effectivement connecté. Si vous demandez à un site Web d’Alterra Mountain Company de mémoriser vos informations de connexion ou d’enregistrer vos préférences, cette information est stockée à l’aide d’un témoin. Certains témoins sont également nécessaires pour permettre le bon fonctionnement de votre transaction (par exemple, mettre des articles dans votre panier).

Nous engageons des tiers pour afficher des publicités en notre nom et pour fournir des données d’analyse. Ces tiers comprennent des réseaux publicitaires (tels que Google AdWords et Facebook Ads) qui utilisent des témoins, des pixels et des technologies similaires pour suivre votre engagement vis-à-vis de nos publicités et pour suivre votre utilisation de nos sites Web et d’autres sites Web. Ces témoins, pixels et technologies similaires aident les réseaux publicitaires à fournir des publicités sur des produits et services adaptés à votre intérêt présumé et à nous fournir des informations sur la façon dont vous interagissez avec le contenu de nos sites Web. Par exemple, le contenu de la page Web sur laquelle vous cliquez, la durée de votre visite sur notre site Web et le site Web que vous avez visité avant le nôtre.

Cette publicité peut apparaître sur notre ou nos sites Web ou sur d’autres sites Web. La technologie de certains de nos réseaux publicitaires utilise des témoins distincts ou d’autres technologies de suivi, y compris des pixels, qui peuvent être délivrés à votre appareil lorsque vous visitez nos sites Web, achetez nos produits, utilisez nos Applications ou ouvrez des courriels de notre part. Ces technologies publicitaires sont régies par la politique de confidentialité de chaque réseau publicitaire tiers. Certains de ces réseaux publicitaires tiers peuvent être membres de la Network Advertising Initiative (NAI). S’ils sont membres de la NAI, vous avez la possibilité de vous désengager. Vous trouverez des informations supplémentaires sur les membres de la NAI et sur la manière de se désengager à l’adresse [https://thenai.org/opt-out.](https://thenai.org/opt-out.)

Le tableau ci-après recense les différents types de témoins que nous et nos prestataires de services utilisons sur nos sites Web et nos Applications, quelques exemples de ceux qui fournissent ces témoins et des liens vers les avis de confidentialité et les informations de désinscription de ces serveurs de témoins. Étant donné que les témoins et les pixels spécifiques que nous pouvons utiliser varient dans le temps, ainsi que selon la page spécifique que vous consultez, le tableau ci-après n’est fourni qu’à titre informatif.

| Type de témoin | Objet | Fournisseur de témoins (à titre d’exemple) |
| --- | --- | --- |
| * * * | * * * | * * * |
| Nécessaires | Ces témoins sont nécessaires au fonctionnement des Services et vous permettent de naviguer à travers les Services et d’utiliser leurs fonctionnalités.  Ces témoins permettent également d’interagir avec les Services, par exemple en nous envoyant un courriel ou en utilisant le service d’assistance à la clientèle par clavardage. La désactivation de ces témoins peut nuire à la performance des Services. | Alterra Mountain Company, Adobe, Google, Microsoft, OneTrust |
| * * * | * * * | * * * |
| Performance | Ces témoins sont nécessaires au fonctionnement des Services et vous permettent de naviguer à travers les Services et d’utiliser leurs fonctionnalités.  La désactivation de ces témoins peut nuire à la performance des Services. Ces témoins, balises et pixels nous permettent d’analyser les activités en lien avec les Services.  Ils peuvent être utilisés pour améliorer le fonctionnement des Services.  À titre d’exemple, ces témoins permettent de reconnaître et de compter le nombre de visiteurs et de voir comment ils naviguent à travers les Services.  Les témoins analytiques nous aident également à mesurer les performances de nos campagnes publicitaires pour les améliorer et optimiser le contenu des Services pour ceux qui interagissent avec notre publicité. | Adobe, Google, Hoefler&Co., Mapbox, Hotjar, Meta, Microsoft, Pingdom, Pinterest, TikTok, Yahoo! |
| * * * | * * * | * * * |
| Marketing | Ces témoins et pixels sont utilisés pour diffuser des publicités pertinentes, suivre les performances des campagnes publicitaires ou le marketing par courriel.  Ces témoins sont utilisés pour vous permettre de partager des pages et du contenu qui vous intéressent sur nos Services par l’intermédiaire de réseaux sociaux tiers et d’autres sites Web.  Ces témoins peuvent également être utilisés à des fins publicitaires. | Google, LinkedIn, Meta, Pinterest, Reddit, Snapchat, TikTok, TV Squared, X, Fyllo, Index Exchange, Jivox, LiveRamp, OpenX, PubMatric, SpotX, StackAdapt, Rubicon, Tapad, TradeDesk, Xandr, Yahoo! |

**Gestion de vos Témoins :** vous pouvez choisir de désactiver certains ou tous les témoins en utilisant le menu des préférences de votre navigateur ou le lien « Vos choix en matière de confidentialité » dans le pied de page de nos sites Web. En désactivant les témoins, nous serons toujours en mesure de suivre votre historique de navigation au cours d’une seule visite sur l’un de nos sites Web, mais cet historique ne nous permettra pas d’établir de lien entre l’historique de navigation au cours de chacune de ces visites et vous, car vous serez considéré comme un nouveau visiteur chaque fois que vous visiterez l’un de nos sites Web. Sachez que la désactivation des témoins peut désactiver certaines fonctions du site Web et empêcher son bon fonctionnement.

**Nos sites Web et nos Applications répondent-ils aux signaux « Do Not Track » (DNT)?**

Nous reconnaissons le mécanisme de confidentialité Global Privacy Control (le« **GPC** »). Votre navigateur doit être en mesure de prendre en charge le GPC pour que nous puissions reconnaître votre signal de préférence de désengagement.

**3\. À QUELLE OCCASION POUVONS-NOUS COMBINER VOS INFORMATIONS PERSONNELLES?**

Nous pouvons combiner les Renseignements personnels que vous fournissez ou que nous recueillons pour mieux comprendre vos besoins, vos exigences et vos préférences personnelles afin d’améliorer nos activités, nos produits, nos services et nos programmes et d’optimiser votre expérience lorsque vous visitez nos stations ou lorsque vous interagissez avec l’un des membres de notre équipe, un représentant du centre d’appels, des agents ou un autre tiers autorisé.

En fonction de vos préférences en matière de marketing, nous pouvons également utiliser ces informations pour vous envoyer des offres, des invitations ou des promotions relatives à nos stations, nos produits, nos services ou nos programmes qui, selon nous, sont susceptibles de vous intéresser. Par exemple, nous pouvons évaluer vos transactions commerciales ou vos habitudes de navigation sur nos sites Web ou dans nos centres, ce qui peut influencer les offres spéciales et les promotions personnalisées que nous vous envoyons.

**4\. DANS QUELS CAS COMMUNIQUONS-NOUS VOS RENSEIGNEMENTS PERSONNELS?**

Nous pouvons fournir vos Renseignements personnels à des prestataires de services et à d’autres tiers dans les cas suivants :

* **Fournisseurs** – Nous pouvons partager vos Renseignements personnels avec des fournisseurs (y compris des sociétés affiliées agissant à ce titre) qui fournissent des services en notre nom, tels que des prestataires de traitement de cartes de paiement, des administrateurs de centres d’appels, des prestataires de services d’hébergement de sites Web, des développeurs d’applications, et des prestataires de gestion de données, de vérification d’identité (par exemple, pour confirmer votre éligibilité à des offres spéciales, telles que des remises militaires), d’analyse de marché, de marketing, de publicité et de gestion de concours, ou vos Renseignements personnels peuvent être recueillis par ces prestataires de services en notre nom.
* **Partenaires du secteur** – Nous pouvons divulguer vos Renseignements personnels à des partenaires tiers dans des situations où la divulgation est nécessaire pour compléter ou fournir les services, les produits (tel qu’un forfait) ou les informations que vous avez achetés ou demandés, ou dans le but d’optimiser les services, les produits ou les informations que vous avez achetés, demandés ou sollicités. À titre d’exemple, nous pouvons divulguer vos Renseignements personnels à un voyagiste tiers si vous avez acheté un circuit auprès de ce voyagiste tiers en utilisant l’un des sites Web de notre station.
* **Stations acceptant nos forfaits** – Lorsque vous balayez certains forfaits dans des Stations acceptant nos forfaits, nous pouvons divulguer vos Renseignements personnels à des Stations acceptant nos forfaits qui ne font pas partie de la famille des stations appartenant à Alterra Mountain Company et exploitées par elle, afin de gérer votre forfait. Lorsque vous balayez votre forfait dans une Station acceptant nos forfaits, veuillez consulter la politique de confidentialité de ladite station.
* **Autres entités du groupe de sociétés d’Alterra Mountain Company** – Les Renseignements personnels relatifs aux clients d’Alterra Mountain Company sont conservés dans une base de données accessible au groupe de sociétés d’Alterra Mountain Company. Nous pouvons combiner ces renseignements avec d’autres informations que nous recueillons à votre propos, mais nous utiliserons toujours les informations comme décrit dans la présente Politique. Cela signifie que les Renseignements personnels recueillis par l’une de nos filiales peuvent être utilisés pour vous envoyer des communications concernant une autre filiale ou des entreprises de notre groupe de sociétés. Le but de ce partage d’informations est de faciliter les réservations des clients dans toutes nos stations et, selon vos préférences en matière de marketing, de permettre à nos entreprises de mieux comprendre vos préférences et de vous envoyer des informations sur nos stations, produits, services et programmes.
* **Alterra Mountain Company Community Foundation** – nous pouvons divulguer à Alterra Mountain Company Community Foundation des renseignements personnels limités à votre sujet, tels que votre nom, votre adresse courriel et le produit acheté, pour la tenue de dossiers internes et les dons futurs, dans la mesure permise par la loi.
* **Transactions d’entreprise** – Nous pouvons divulguer vos Renseignements personnels à une autre entité, si nécessaire, dans le cas d’une fusion, d’une vente, d’une transaction d’entreprise ou d’une réorganisation réelle ou proposée, y compris dans le cadre d’une procédure d’insolvabilité ou de faillite, ou dans le but d’évaluer et/ou de réaliser une telle transaction. Par ailleurs, lorsque nous concluons une transaction avec un tiers, nous pouvons recevoir des Renseignements personnels dans le cadre du devoir de diligence. Une fois une transaction conclue, le tiers peut transférer des Renseignements personnels, que nous utiliserons comme décrit dans la présente Politique.
* **Circonstances particulières** – Nous pouvons juger nécessaire ou être tenus par la loi de divulguer vos Renseignements personnels à nos avocats, à d’autres personnes légalement autorisées dans certaines situations d’urgence où la santé, la sécurité ou le bien-être d’une personne est en danger imminent, aux forces de l’ordre ou à d’autres parties pour se conformer à une décision de justice, telle qu’une assignation, ou d’une quelconque autre manière requise pour se conformer à la loi.

**5\. VOTRE CONSENTEMENT**

Nous recueillons, utilisons et divulguons vos Renseignements personnels de la manière décrite dans la présente Politique et avec votre consentement, sauf lorsque la loi l’autorise ou l’exige. Il se peut que nous soyons tenus ou autorisés, en vertu d’une loi ou d’une réglementation, à recueillir, utiliser ou divulguer des Renseignements personnels sans votre consentement, notamment afin de respecter une décision de justice, de recouvrer une dette qui nous est due ou s’il existe une menace imminente pour la santé, la sécurité ou le bien-être d’une personne.

Votre consentement peut être explicite (ex. : oral, écrit ou électronique) ou raisonnablement déduit ou implicite de par vos actions (ex. : l’utilisation de nos sites Web implique le consentement au recueil, à l’utilisation et à la divulgation de vos Renseignements personnels comme décrit dans cette Politique). Dans certains cas, un représentant autorisé peut consentir en votre nom. Dans le cas d’enfants mineurs, un parent ou un tuteur légal peut consentir à ce que nous recueillions, utilisions et divulguions les Renseignements personnels d’un mineur dans le cadre de l’achat et de la gestion d’un produit, tel qu’un forfait ou un service. Pour plus d’informations sur la manière dont nous obtenons le consentement parental, veuillez consulter la section « Confidentialité des enfants » ci-dessous.

Vous pouvez retirer votre consentement à tout moment, sous réserve des restrictions légales ou contractuelles, en nous contactant comme indiqué dans la section « Vos options en matière de confidentialité » de la présente Politique. Cependant, le retrait de votre consentement pourrait affecter votre expérience et notre capacité à vous fournir des produits ou des services, ou un service rapide et précis, soit en ligne, soit par l’intermédiaire de nos agents de service.

Si vous ne consentez pas au recueil, à l’utilisation et à la divulgation de vos Renseignements personnels en ligne comme décrit dans la présente Politique, n’utilisez pas nos sites Web, nos Applications et n’achetez pas nos produits ou services.

**6\. COMMENT GÉRER VOS PRÉFÉRENCES EN MATIÈRE DE MARKETING**

Si vous ne voulez plus que nous utilisions vos Renseignements personnels à des fins de marketing, notamment pour vous envoyer des communications promotionnelles, vous pouvez nous contacter comme indiqué dans la section « Vos options en matière de confidentialité » de la présente Politique et demander votre retrait de nos listes de contacts et/ou de diffusion. Il se peut que nous vous demandions des informations supplémentaires, le cas échéant, afin de vous identifier correctement. Si vous vous désabonnez des communications marketing, veuillez noter que nous pouvons encore avoir besoin de vous contacter pour d’autres questions telles que celles relatives à une transaction d’achat ou à la gestion de votre forfait.

Vous pouvez également gérer vos abonnements aux courriels en cliquant sur « Se désabonner » au bas de chacun de nos courriels que vous recevez pour ne plus recevoir de communications promotionnelles par courriel de notre part.

Si vous souhaitez ne plus recevoir de SMS de notre part, veuillez répondre « STOP » au SMS.

**7\. CONFIDENTIALITÉ DES ENFANTS**

**Enfants de moins de 13 ans :** Nous ne recueillons pas sciemment les Renseignements personnels d’enfants de moins de treize ans sans le consentement préalable et vérifié d’un parent ou d’un tuteur légal. Le site Web et les pages de médias sociaux d’Alterra Mountain Company disponibles en ligne ne sont pas destinés aux utilisateurs de moins de treize ans. La présente Politique, ainsi que tout autre formulaire de consentement parental fourni dans le cadre de la prestation des Services aux enfants, décrit nos pratiques en matière de confidentialité, y compris la manière dont nous recueillons et traitons les informations concernant votre enfant. Si vous pensez que votre enfant de moins de treize ans a pu nous fournir des Renseignements personnels en ligne, veuillez nous contacter à [yourprivacy@alterramtnco.com](mailto:yourprivacy@alterramtnco.com) pour que nous puissions prendre les mesures adéquates.

Le consentement d’un parent ou d’un tuteur de l’enfant est requis pour qu’un enfant de moins de 13 ans puisse ouvrir un compte ou créer un profil lié à une Application. Les parents et tuteurs comprennent que l’Application peut recueillir des informations sur leur enfant, telles que des photos, des sessions de clavardage, des données de localisation et des informations sur les remontées mécaniques empruntées par l’enfant lors de sa séance de ski ou de planche à neige. L’objectif de ce recueil d’informations se limite à la prestation des Services des applications. Nous ne recueillons ni n’utilisons ces informations pour commercialiser des produits ou des services aux enfants, et nous nous engageons à ne pas vendre ces informations. Vous pouvez demander à tout moment la suppression des Renseignements personnels de votre enfant. Vous avez le droit de consentir au recueil et à l’utilisation des Renseignements personnels de votre enfant de notre part tout en interdisant leur divulgation à des tiers. Vous pouvez consulter, supprimer ou interdire le recueil des Renseignements personnels de votre enfant à tout moment. Pour désactiver le compte de votre enfant, demander une copie des renseignements ou poser une question sur les Applications et les données de votre enfant, les parents et les tuteurs doivent contacter notre Responsable de la confidentialité à l’adresse [yourprivacy@alterramtnco.com](mailto:yourprivacy@alterramtnco.com).

**8\. DURÉE DE CONSERVATION DE VOS RENSEIGNEMENTS PERSONNELS**

Nous conserverons vos Renseignements personnels dans nos dossiers aussi longtemps qu’il le faudra pour réaliser l’objectif pour lequel ils ont été fournis, répondre à nos objectifs commerciaux, remplir nos obligations légales et, le cas échéant, les besoins des parties auxquelles nous les divulguons, y compris les Stations acceptant nos forfaits. Nous pouvons conserver vos Renseignements personnels plus longtemps à des fins spécifiques dans la mesure où nous y sommes obligés par la législation ou la réglementation, pour vous protéger, protéger autrui et nous protéger contre la fraude, l’abus, l’accès non autorisé, si cela est nécessaire pour protéger nos droits légaux ou pour répondre à certaines exigences commerciales.

Nous nous engageons à supprimer vos Renseignements personnels lorsqu’ils ne sont plus nécessaires aux fins pour lesquelles ils ont été fournis, ou dès lors que vous en faites la demande, sous réserve des exceptions mentionnées dans la présente Politique ou en vertu de toute loi, de tout contrat ou de tout règlement applicable.

Si vous utilisez notre ou nos Applications, vous pouvez supprimer votre compte depuis la ou les Applications. Si vous supprimez votre compte depuis la ou les Applications, nous supprimerons les Renseignements personnels qui s’y rapportent.

**9\. COMMENT NOUS PROTÉGEONS VOS DONNÉES**

Nous avons à cœur de protéger vos Renseignements personnels. Nous prenons diverses mesures raisonnables, organisationnelles, administratives et techniques (décrites ci-dessous) pour protéger vos Renseignements personnels contre l’accès, la divulgation, l’altération ou la destruction non autorisés. Toutefois, nous ne sommes pas en mesure de garantir une sécurité totale, car le risque zéro n’existe pas sur Internet.

Si la loi nous y oblige, nous vous informerons et/ou nous informerons l’autorité de contrôle compétente en cas de violation de données.

Vos Renseignements personnels peuvent être conservés sur nos serveurs ou ceux de nos prestataires de services et accessibles par nos employés, prestataires de services et représentants autorisés. Nous observons des contrôles, des calendriers et des pratiques raisonnables et systématiques pour conserver et détruire les Renseignements personnels.

**Protections internes :** Nous protégeons les Renseignements personnels par des mesures de sécurité adaptées au niveau de sensibilité des informations. Nous avons des politiques et des pratiques pour nous protéger contre la perte, le vol, l’accès non autorisé, la divulgation, la copie, l’utilisation, la modification ou la destruction. Bien que nous déployons tous les efforts nécessaires pour protéger vos Renseignements personnels, nous ne sommes pas en mesure de garantir que vos Renseignements personnels seront toujours sécurisés. Des facteurs indépendants de notre volonté peuvent entraîner la perte ou le vol, ou l’accès, l’utilisation ou la divulgation non autorisés de vos Renseignements personnels. Par conséquent, nous ne donnons aucune garantie et ne faisons aucune déclaration sur la non-divulgation de vos Renseignements personnels. Nous employons également un Responsable de la confidentialité, chargé de veiller au respect de ces politiques et que vous pouvez contacter à l’adresse ci-dessous pour toute question, préoccupation ou plainte.

**Protections externes :** Pour protéger les informations divulguées aux prestataires de services, nous utilisons des moyens contractuels ou autres pour assurer un niveau de protection similaire afin que les prestataires de services traitent les informations de manière confidentielle, mettent en œuvre des mesures de sécurité appropriées et n’utilisent et ne divulguent les informations que dans le but de fournir les services pertinents.

**10\. OÙ CONSERVONS-NOUS VOS RENSEIGNEMENTS PERSONNELS?**

Sachez que vos Renseignements personnels peuvent être transférés, stockés et traités par nous et nos sociétés affiliées au Canada et aux États-Unis où Alterra Mountain Company, ses sociétés affiliées ou ses prestataires de services exploitent et conservent des données. Si vous êtes citoyen ou citoyenne d’un pays autre que les États-Unis, vos Renseignements personnels seront assujettis aux lois américaines applicables, qui peuvent permettre aux autorités gouvernementales, réglementaires ou de sécurité nationale étrangères d’avoir accès à vos Renseignements personnels dans certains cas. En nous fournissant vos Renseignements personnels, vous comprenez et acceptez que vos Renseignements personnels puissent être transférés dans nos installations aux États-Unis, traités par nous aux États-Unis, stockés aux États-Unis et transférés à ceux avec qui nous les partageons comme décrit dans la présente Politique.

**11\. VOS OPTIONS ET VOS DROITS EN MATIÈRE DE CONFIDENTIALITÉ**

_(a) Clients situés en Californie_

Si vous résidez en Californie, vous disposez de certains droits en ce qui concerne la collecte, l’utilisation, le transfert et le traitement de vos Renseignements personnels, comme défini par la Loi californienne sur la protection de la vie privée des consommateurs (California Consumer Privacy Act), par la section 1798.100 _et seq_ du Code civil de la Californie, Code § 1798.100 _et seq_., comme modifiée par la loi californienne sur les droits à la vie privée et ses règlements d’application (collectivement, la « **CCPA** »). Nous nous réservons le droit de limiter ces droits lorsque la loi applicable l’autorise, notamment lorsque votre identité ne peut être raisonnablement vérifiée ou dans la mesure où vos droits portent atteinte aux droits et libertés d’autrui. Veuillez noter que les termes de cette section sur les droits de la protection de la vie privée en Californie sont utilisés conformément aux définitions qui leur sont données dans le CPRA, qui peuvent différer de la façon dont ces termes sont utilisés dans le reste de la Politique de confidentialité (le terme « partager », notamment).

**Quels renseignements recueillons-nous?**

Les exemples ci-dessous sont extraits de la CCPA et ne reflètent pas les informations spécifiques que nous collectons.

Au cours des douze derniers mois, nous avons recueilli les catégories de Renseignements personnels suivants :

| Catégorie | Exemples | Recueillis | Durée de conservation |
| --- | --- | --- | --- |
| * * * | * * * | * * * | * * * |
| A. Identifiants | Un nom réel, un pseudonyme, une adresse postale, un identifiant personnel unique, un identifiant en ligne, une adresse IP, une adresse courriel, un nom de compte, un numéro de sécurité sociale, un numéro de permis de conduire, un numéro de passeport ou d’autres identifiants similaires. | Oui | Pour réaliser l’objectif commercial pour lequel ils ont été fournis ou si la loi l’exige |
| * * * | * * * | * * * | * * * |
| B. Renseignements personnels | Un nom, une signature, un numéro de sécurité sociale, des caractéristiques physiques ou une description physique, une adresse, un numéro de téléphone, un numéro de cellulaire, un numéro de passeport, un numéro de permis de conduire ou de carte d’identité nationale, un numéro de permis de police d’assurance, des informations liées au parcours de formation ou d’emploi, des antécédents professionnels, un numéro de compte bancaire, un numéro de carte de crédit, un numéro de carte de débit, ou toute autre information financière, médicale ou d’assurance maladie.   Certains renseignements personnels de cette catégorie peuvent également se retrouver dans d’autres catégories. | Oui | Pour réaliser l’objectif commercial pour lequel ils ont été fournis ou si la loi l’exige |
| * * * | * * * | * * * | * * * |
| C. Caractéristiques de classification protégées en vertu de la loi californienne ou fédérale | L’âge (à partir de 40 ans), la race, la couleur de peau, l’ascendance, l’origine nationale, la citoyenneté, la religion ou les croyances, l’état civil, l’état de santé, le handicap physique ou mental, le sexe (y compris le genre, l’identité de genre, l’expression de genre, la grossesse ou l’accouchement et les problèmes de santé connexes), l’orientation sexuelle, le statut d’ancien combattant ou de militaire, les informations génétiques (y compris les informations génétiques familiales). | Oui | Pour réaliser l’objectif commercial pour lequel ils ont été fournis ou si la loi l’exige |
| * * * | * * * | * * * | * * * |
| D. Informations commerciales | Dossiers concernant des biens personnels, des produits ou des services achetés, obtenus ou consultés, ou autres historiques ou tendances d’achat ou de consommation. | Oui | Pour réaliser l’objectif commercial pour lequel ils ont été fournis ou si la loi l’exige |
| * * * | * * * | * * * | * * * |
| E. Informations biométriques | Caractéristiques physiologiques et comportementales, notamment les informations concernant la santé, le poids, la pointure ou l’activité physique. | Oui | Pour réaliser l’objectif commercial pour lequel ils ont été fournis ou si la loi l’exige |
| * * * | * * * | * * * | * * * |
| F. Activité sur Internet ou sur d’autres réseaux similaires | Historique de navigation, historique de recherche, informations sur l’interaction d’un consommateur avec un site Web, une application ou une publicité. | Oui | Pour réaliser l’objectif commercial pour lequel ils ont été fournis ou si la loi l’exige |
| * * * | * * * | * * * | * * * |
| G. Donnée de géolocalisation | Emplacement physique ou mouvements. | Oui | Pour réaliser l’objectif commercial pour lequel ils ont été fournis ou si la loi l’exige |
| * * * | * * * | * * * | * * * |
| H. Données sensorielles | Informations sonores, électroniques, visuelles ou similaires, telles que l’utilisation de caméras de vidéosurveillance ou autre technologie. | Oui | Pour réaliser l’objectif commercial pour lequel ils ont été fournis ou si la loi l’exige |
| * * * | * * * | * * * | * * * |
| I. Informations professionnelles ou liées à l’emploi | Salaire ou niveau de revenu | Non | S.O. |
| * * * | * * * | * * * | * * * |
| J. Informations éducatives non publiques | Niveau d’éducation atteint. | Non | S.O. |
| * * * | * * * | * * * | * * * |
| K. Déductions tirées d’autres informations sur le consommateur | Déductions tirées de renseignements personnels identifiés ci-dessus pour créer un profil concernant un consommateur, qui reflète ses préférences, caractéristiques, prédispositions, comportements, attitudes, intelligence, capacités et aptitudes. | Oui | Pour réaliser l’objectif commercial pour lequel ils ont été fournis ou si la loi l’exige |
| * * * | * * * | * * * | * * * |
| L. Renseignements personnels sensibles | Renseignements personnels qui révèlent (a) le numéro de sécurité sociale, de permis de conduire, de carte d’identité ou de passeport; (b) le numéro de connexion au compte, de compte financier, de carte de débit ou de crédit en combinaison avec tout code de sécurité ou d’accès, le mot de passe ou des identifiants permettant l’accès à un compte; (c) la géolocalisation précise; (d) l’origine raciale ou ethnique, les croyances religieuses ou philosophiques, ou l’appartenance à un syndicat; (e) le contenu du courrier, des courriels et des SMS d’un consommateur, sauf si l’entreprise est le destinataire prévu de la communication; ou (f) des données génétiques.    Informations biométriques traitées dans le but d’identifier un consommateur de manière unique, les renseignements personnels recueillis et analysés concernant la santé, la vie sexuelle ou l’orientation sexuelle d’un consommateur.   Certains Renseignements personnels sensibles de cette catégorie peuvent également se retrouver dans d’autres catégories. | Oui | Pour réaliser l’objectif commercial pour lequel ils ont été fournis ou si la loi l’exige |

**D’où proviennent les Renseignements personnels?**

Nous recueillons les Renseignements personnels directement auprès de vous, lors de vos interactions avec nos sites Web, nos Applications et nos Services, auprès de sources accessibles au public et auprès de tiers qui recueillent les renseignements personnels directement auprès de vous.

**Fins professionnelles et commerciales pour lesquelles les Renseignements personnels sont recueillis**

Vos Renseignements personnels sont utilisés aux fins suivantes :

* Pour présenter nos Services, nos sites Web et nos Applications et leur contenu de manière adaptée et efficace pour vous et votre appareil;
* Pour être en conformité avec la loi;
* Pour vous contacter afin de vous fournir les informations ou les services pour lesquels vous nous avez sollicités;
* Pour communiquer sur des opportunités, des services ou des évènements spéciaux que nous pensons susceptibles de vous intéresser;
* Pour fournit une assistance à la clientèle, résoudre les problèmes, gérer les comptes et répondre aux demandes, questions ou commentaires;
* Pour remplir nos obligations et faire respecter nos droits découlant de tout contrat; et
* Pour vous informer de tout ajout, de toute mise à niveau ou de toute modification concernant nos services.

**Tiers à qui nous divulguons, partageons ou vendons les Renseignements personnels**

Au cours des 12 derniers mois, nous avons divulgué les renseignements personnels ci-après à propos de consommateurs, à des fins professionnelles :

* Nous divulguons aux prestataires de services les Renseignements personnels des catégories A (Identifiants), B (Personnels), C (Classifications protégées), D (Commerciaux), F (Internet), G (Géolocalisation), K (Déductions) et L (Renseignements personnels sensibles). Nous divulguons le contenu publié sur nos plateformes de médias sociaux (à titre d’exemple, si un consommateur « commente » une actualité) à d’autres consommateurs. Ces publications peuvent inclure des Renseignements personnels des catégories A et B, mais leur contenu dépend de chaque publication.
* Nous pouvons divulguer toutes vos informations, y compris vos Renseignements personnels, à nos filiales et à nos sociétés affiliées dans le cadre de la fourniture des Services ou d’autres opérations commerciales.

Au cours des 12 derniers mois, nous avons partagé, à des fins de publicité comportementale intercontextuelle, les Renseignements personnels des catégories A (Identifiants), B (Personnels), D (Commerciaux), F (Internet), G (Géolocalisation), et K (Déductions).

Au cours des douze (12) derniers mois, nous n’avons vendu les Renseignements personnels d’aucun consommateur à titre pécuniaire. Toutefois, le fait que nous utilisions des témoins de connexion et autres technologies de suivi peut être considéré comme une vente de Renseignements personnels au titre de la CCPA. Les Renseignements personnels que nous avons vendus au sens de la CCPA relevaient des catégories suivantes : A (Identifiants), B (Personnels), D (Commerciaux), F (Internet), G (Géolocalisation), et K (Déductions). Les catégories de tiers auxquels les Renseignements personnels sont vendus au sens de la CCPA comprennent les fournisseurs d’analyse de données et les fournisseurs de publicité et de marketing.

Vous pouvez refuser nos technologies de suivi pour les fournisseurs de services d’analyse et de publicité en cliquant sur le lien « Vos choix en matière de confidentialité » dans le pied de page de nos sites Web. Veuillez noter que votre utilisation de notre site Web sera toujours suivie par Alterra Mountain Company et ses fournisseurs de services.

A notre connaissance, nous ne vendons ou ne partageons pas les Renseignements personnels de consommateurs âgés de moins de seize (16) ans.

**Droits individuels**

a. Droit d’être informé(e) sur les Renseignements personnels recueillis, divulgués, partagés ou vendus

Vous avez le droit de nous demander de divulguer à des tiers les Renseignements personnels que nous recueillons, utilisons et divulguons vous concernant. Vous pouvez formuler deux types de demandes liées à votre Droit d’être informé(e)

1. Droit d’être informé(e) (Demande abrégée) : Si vous formulez une demande liée à votre Droit d’être informé(e) (Demande abrégée), vous recevrez les informations ci-après à votre sujet :
    1. Catégories de Renseignements personnels recueillis, vendus ou partagés;
    2. Catégories de sources d’où proviennent les Renseignements personnels;
    3. Catégories de tiers à qui les renseignements sont vendus, partagés ou divulgués;
    4. Les fins professionnelles ou commerciales de cette collecte, ce partage ou cette vente de Renseignements personnels;
    5. Catégories de Renseignements personnels divulgués à des fins professionnelles et catégories de personnes auxquelles ils ont été divulgués à des fins professionnelles.
2. Droit d’être informé(e) (Demande de renseignements spécifiques) : Si vous formulez une demande liée à votre Droit d’être informé(e) (Demande de renseignements spécifiques), vous recevrez les informations ci-après à votre sujet :
    1. Éléments précis des Renseignements personnels recueillis à votre sujet.

Ces renseignements vous seront fournis gratuitement, sauf si nous estimons que votre demande est manifestement infondée ou excessive. Vous pouvez formuler ce type de demande deux fois par période de 12 mois. Le Droit d’être informé(e) du consommateur comporte certaines exceptions. Nous indiquerons dans notre réponse si une exception s’applique.

b. Droit de suppression

Vous avez le droit de demander que nous et nos prestataires de services supprimions l’un quelconque des Renseignements personnels vous concernant que nous avons recueillis auprès de vous, à la réception d’une demande vérifiable. Ce droit est soumis à certaines exceptions. Nous indiquerons dans notre réponse si une exception s’applique.

c. Droit de refuser la vente ou le partage de Renseignements personnels

Vous avez le droit de refuser la vente ou le partage de vos Renseignements personnels par une entreprise soumise à certaines lois et réglementations. Pour en savoir plus, veuillez cliquer sur le lien « Vos choix en matière de confidentialité » dans le pied de page de nos sites Web. Vous pouvez également exprimer votre refus en utilisant le signal GPC (Global Privacy Control).

Veuillez noter que vos préférences en matière de refus peuvent être enregistrées par le biais des témoins de connexion. Si vous supprimez les témoins de connexion, si votre navigateur bloque les témoins de connexion ou si vous consultez la page à partir d’un autre navigateur ou d’un autre appareil, il se peut que votre préférence en matière de refus ne soit plus enregistrée ou reconnue.

d. Droit d’être protégé(e) contre la discrimination

Vous avez le droit de ne pas faire l’objet d’un traitement discriminatoire pour avoir exercé les droits à la vie privée conférés par la loi californienne. Nous n’agirons pas de manière discriminatoire envers vous parce que vous avez exercé l’un de vos droits en matière de protection de la vie privée, notamment en vous refusant des biens et services; en appliquant des prix ou des tarifs différents pour des biens ou services; y compris par le biais de remises ou autres avantages ou en imposant des pénalités; en vous fournissant un niveau de qualité différent pour les biens ou les services; ou en suggérant que vous recevrez un prix ou un tarif différent pour les biens ou les services ou un niveau ou une qualité différents pour les biens ou services. Nous n’exercerons pas de représailles à l’encontre d’un employé, d’un candidat à l’emploi ou d’un entrepreneur indépendant pour avoir exercé ses droits en vertu de la CCPA.

e. Droit de rectification

Si nous détenons des Renseignements personnels erronés à votre sujet, vous avez le droit de demander que nous rectifiions les Renseignements personnels erronés dès la réception de votre demande vérifiable. En tenant compte de la nature des Renseignements personnels et des finalités de traitement des Renseignements personnels, vous avez le droit de demande que nous rectifions les Renseignements personnels à votre sujet, le cas échéant.

f. Droit de limiter l’utilisation et la divulgation des Renseignements personnels sensibles

Si nous avons à traiter des Renseignements personnels sensibles, nous le ferons uniquement aux fins spécifiquement autorisées par la loi californienne et d’une manière qui est nécessaire et proportionnée à ces objectifs. Ainsi, nous n’effectuons aucun traitement pour lequel une demande liée au Droit de limitation est possible.

g. Transmission de demandes

Vous pouvez transmettre votre demande en cliquant sur notre lien **« Vos choix en matière de confidentialité »** dans le pied de page de nos sites Web ou en téléphonant au numéro gratuit suivant : 1-866-675-7529 et en laissant un message détaillé, votre prénom et nom de famille, votre date de naissance, votre courriel et votre code postal, ainsi que vos instructions pour la rectification. Veuillez fournir les renseignements associés à votre compte ou que vous utilisez pour effectuer des transactions avec Alterra Mountain Company. Vous devez fournir tous les renseignements requis pour soumettre une demande. Seules les demandes complètes reçues par le bureau de la protection de la vie privée d’Alterra Mountain Company, qui comprennent tous les renseignements requis et qui correspondent aux renseignements figurant dans nos dossiers, seront traitées. Pour votre sécurité, il se peut que nous vous demandions plus d’informations si nécessaire pour vérifier votre identité. En cas de refus de notre part, nous vous en fournirons la raison.

h. Vérification des demandes

Pour assurer la protection de vos Renseignements personnels, nous devons vérifier que la personne

qui nous transmet une demande d’information, une demande de suppression ou une demande de rectification est bien le consommateur qui est concerné par la demande avant que celle-ci ne soit traitée. Pour vérifier l’identité d’un consommateur californien, nous sommes susceptibles de lui demander jusqu’à quatre éléments d’information (notamment votre nom, votre date de naissance, votre adresse courriel et/ou votre code postal). Veuillez fournir les renseignements associés à votre compte ou que vous utilisez pour effectuer des transactions avec Alterra Mountain Company. Nous pouvons également demander au consommateur dont les Renseignements personnels font l’objet de la demande de signer une déclaration sur l’honneur.

Le fait de présenter une demande vérifiable de consommateur ne vous oblige pas à créer un compte chez nous.

Nous n’utiliserons les Renseignements personnels fournis dans votre demande que pour vérifier votre identité et nous supprimerons toutes les informations que vous aurez fournies après avoir traité cette demande. Nous nous réservons le droit de prendre toute mesure supplémentaire qui s’impose pour pouvoir vérifier l’identité des consommateurs californiens lorsque nous avons des raisons de penser qu’une demande est frauduleuse.

i. Agents autorisés

Vous pouvez choisir une personne ou une entreprise enregistrée auprès du Secrétaire d’État de Californie que vous autorisez à agir en votre nom pour transmettre vos demandes (« Agent autorisé »). Si vous choisissez d’avoir recours à un Agent autorisé, nous vous demandons de bien vouloir fournir une autorisation écrite audit Agent autorisé pour lui permettre de présenter votre demande et de bien vouloir vérifier votre identité directement auprès de nous. A défaut, Alterra Mountain Company pourra refuser votre demande.

Nous nous réservons le droit de ne pas répondre aux demandes envoyées plus d’une fois par année civile, ou aux demandes transmises à une adresse autre que celle indiquée dans la présente politique.

_(b) Clients situés dans le Colorado, dans le Connecticut, dans l’Utah et en Virginie_

Les personnes résidant dans le Colorado, dans le Connecticut, dans l’Utah et en Virginie ont certains droits en ce qui concerne leurs données. Ces droits sont consacrés par la Colorado Privacy Act (la « **CPA** »), le Connecticut Data Privacy Act (« la **CTDPA** »), l’Utah Consumer Privacy Act (« l’**UCPA** »), et la Virginia Consumer Data Protection Act (la « **VCDPA** »). Le tableau ci-dessous donne une explication détaillée de ces droits et dresse la liste des États dont les résidents peuvent exercer lesdits droits. Pour exercer l’un quelconque des droits énumérés dans le tableau ci-dessous, veuillez cliquer sur le lien « Vos choix en matière de confidentialité » dans le pied de page de nos sites Web ou téléphoner au 1-866-675-7529 et veuillez suivre les instructions énoncées dans la partie « Vos options en matière de confidentialité ».

| Droit du consommateur | Explication | Applicable aux résidents de/du : |
| --- | --- | --- |
| * * * | * * * | * * * |
| Droit d’être informé(e)/d’accès | Vous avez le droit de savoir si nous traitons vos données à caractère personnel et le droit d’accéder à ces données. | Colorado, Connecticut, Utah, Virginie |
| * * * | * * * | * * * |
| Droit de rectification | Vous avez le droit de corriger les inexactitudes dans vos données à caractère personnel, en tenant compte de la nature des données à caractère personnel et des finalités de traitement des données à caractère personnel. | Colorado, Connecticut, Virginie |
| * * * | * * * | * * * |
| Droit de suppression | Vous avez le droit à la suppression, sous réserve de certaines exceptions, les données à caractère personnel que vous nous avez fournies ou que nous avons obtenues à votre sujet. \*Remarque : Si vous résidez dans l’Utah, cela ne s’applique qu’aux données à caractère personnel que vous nous avez directement fournies. | Colorado, Connecticut, Utah\*, Virginie |
| * * * | * * * | * * * |
| Droit à la portabilité | Vous avez le droit, deux fois par année civile maximum, d’obtenir vos données à caractère personnel dans un format portable et, dans la mesure où cela est techniquement possible, facilement utilisable, qui vous permette de transmettre les données à une autre entité, sans entrave.  Ce droit peut être exercé en combinaison avec le Droit à être informé(e)/d’accès.  Pour exercer ce Droit à la portabilité, veuillez suivre les instructions relatives à l’exercice de votre droit à être informé(e)/d’accès décrites à la page « Vos choix en matière de confidentialité ».  \*Remarque : Si vous résidez dans l’Utah, cela ne s’applique qu’au traitement effectué par des moyens automatisés. | Colorado, Connecticut, Utah\*, Virginie |
| * * * | * * * | * * * |
| Droit de refus : Colorado, Connecticut et Virginie | Vous avez le droit de refuser le traitement de vos données à caractère personnel pour les finalités suivantes : (1)   Publicité ciblée; (2)   La vente de données à caractère personnel; et/ou (3)   le profilage en vue de décisions qui produisent des effets juridiques ou des effets similaires significatifs à votre égard.  Pour exprimer votre refus, veuillez consulter la page « Vos choix en matière de confidentialité ». | Colorado, Connecticut, Virginie |
| * * * | * * * | * * * |
| Droit de refus : Utah | Vous avez le droit de refuser la vente de vos données à caractère personnel ou la publicité ciblée. Pour exprimer votre refus, veuillez consulter la page « Vos choix en matière de confidentialité ». | Utah |

**Données sensibles**

Les Données sensibles, telles que définies dans la CPA, la CTDPA, l’UCPA, et la VCDPA comprennent des informations de géolocalisation précises, l’origine raciale ou ethnique d’une personne, son état de santé mentale ou physique ou son diagnostic, son orientation sexuelle et son statut de citoyen.Nous ne recueillerons pas ces informations auprès des résidents du Connecticut et de la Virginie sans avoir obtenu préalablement leur consentement.Nous ne recueillerons pas ces informations auprès des résidents de l’Utah sans les en avoir informés clairement et leur donner la possibilité de refuser le traitement.Nous ne recueillerons pas ces informations auprès des résidents du Colorado sans avoir obtenu préalablement leur consentement. Veuillez noter que la collecte et le traitement des Données sensibles (telles que définies dans certaines lois nationales) sont nécessaires à la gestion des Services.

**Exercer vos droits**

Si vous résidez au Colorado, au Connecticut, en Utah ou en Virginie et souhaitez exercer l’un des droits susmentionnés et qu’il s’applique à vous, veuillez cliquer sur le lien **« Vos choix en matière de confidentialité »** dans le pied de page de nos sites Web. Nous pourrions avoir besoin de vous demander des informations supplémentaires pour nous permettre de vérifier votre identité et votre demande.

Il peut arriver qu’une demande soit faite au nom de quelqu’un d’autre (ex. : si vous êtes un représentant dûment mandaté ou le parent ou tuteur d’un enfant au nom duquel vous souhaitez exercer ses droits).

Nous nous engageons à répondre à la demande d’un consommateur, le cas échéant, dans un délai de 45 jours à compter de la réception de ladite demande et sans retard injustifié. Dans le cas où nous devrions prolonger cette période, nous nous engageons à vous en informer et à vous fournir la justification raisonnablement nécessaire y afférente.

Nous vous répondrons gratuitement, sous réserve des exclusions qui s’appliquent dans l’État où vous résidez. Des frais s’appliquent dans les cas suivants :

* Colorado, Connecticut et Utah - si vous transmettez plus d’une demande sur une période de douze mois; et
* Connecticut et Virginie - si votre demande est manifestement infondée, excessive ou répétitive.

**Faire appel d’une décision liée à l’exercice de vos droits**

Si vous êtes résident ou résidente du Colorado, du Connecticut ou de la Virginie et que nous refusons d’agir ou que nous n’agissons pas suite à une demande de votre part concernant l’exercice de vos droits légitimes en tant que consommateur, vous êtes en droit de faire appel. Pour ce faire, veuillez nous écrire à [yourprivacy@alterramtnco.com](mailto:yourprivacy@alterramtnco.com). Dans ce courriel d’appel, veuillez préciser le ou les droits concernés et la date à laquelle vous aviez transmis ladite demande.

Nous vous informerons par écrit, dans un délai de 45 jours, de toute mesure qui a été prise ou non en réponse à cet appel. Nous vous fournirons également une explication écrite des raisons de nos décisions concernant votre ou vos demandes.

_(c) Clients situés dans l’Union européenne, en Suisse et au Royaume-Uni_

Cette section de la Politique de confidentialité s’applique aux clients situés dans l’Union européenne (« **UE** »), dans un État membre de l’Espace économique européen (« **EEE** »), au Royaume-Uni (« **R-U** »), ou en Suisse, ainsi qu’aux personnes dont les Renseignements personnels font l’objet d’un traitement dans l’UE, l’EEE, le R-U ou la Suisse ou d’un transfert depuis l’UE, l’EEE, le R-U ou la Suisse.En vertu du Règlement général sur la protection des données de l’UE et du Règlement général sur la protection des données du R-U (collectivement, le « **RGPD** »), vous avez droit aux informations contenues dans la présente section de notre Politique de confidentialité.

**Vos** **droits**

La loi vous autorise à accéder, rectifier, modifier ou supprimer les Renseignements personnels que nous détenons à votre sujet.Un résumé de ces droits figure ci-dessous.Veuillez noter que ces droits ne sont pas absolus et que certaines exemptions peuvent s’appliquer à des demandes spécifiques que vous pouvez nous soumettre.

Pour exercer ces droits, veuillez cliquer sur notre lien **« Vos choix en matière de confidentialité »** dans le pied de page de nos sites Web ou en téléphonant au numéro gratuit suivant : 1-866-675-7529 et en laissant un message détaillé, votre prénom et nom de famille, votre date de naissance, votre courriel et votre code postal, ainsi que vos instructions pour la rectification. Veuillez fournir les renseignements associés à votre compte ou que vous utilisez pour effectuer des transactions avec Alterra Mountain Company. Vous devez fournir tous les renseignements requis pour soumettre une demande. Seules les demandes complètes reçues par le bureau de la protection de la vie privée d’Alterra Mountain Company, qui comprennent tous les renseignements requis et qui correspondent aux renseignements figurant dans nos dossiers, seront traitées. Pour votre sécurité, il se peut que nous vous demandions plus d’informations si nécessaire pour vérifier votre identité. En cas de refus de notre part, nous vous en fournirons la raison.

_Demande d’accès à vos Renseignements personnels_

Vous avez le droit d’obtenir de notre part la confirmation que nous traitons ou non des Renseignements personnels vous concernant et, dans l’affirmative, le droit de recevoir les informations contenues dans la présente Politique.Vous avez également le droit de nous demander des copies de vos Renseignements personnels.Dans votre demande, veuillez indiquer clairement les Renseignements personnels auxquels vous souhaitez avoir accès. Lorsque les demandes sont répétitives ou manifestement infondées ou excessives, nous sommes en droit de facturer des frais raisonnables basés sur les coûts administratifs.

_Demande de rectification de vos Renseignements personnels_

Vous avez le droit de nous demander de rectifier les renseignements que vous estimez erronés.Vous avez également le droit de nous demander de compléter les renseignements que vous estimez incomplets.

_Demande de suppression de vos Renseignements personnels_

Vous avez le droit de nous demander de supprimer vos Renseignements personnels si :

* Nous n’en avons plus besoin aux fins pour lesquelles nous les avons collectées;
* Nous les avons utilisés sans base juridique valable;
* Nous sommes légalement tenus de les supprimer;
* Vous avez retiré votre consentement. Or, nous en avons besoin pour utiliser lesdits renseignements; ou
* Vous vous opposez à ce que nous traitions vos Renseignements personnels lorsque notre base juridique repose sur nos intérêts légitimes et qu’il n’existe pas de motifs légitimes prépondérants pour le traitement.

Toutefois, il ne s’agit pas d’un droit absolu.Même si vous demandez la suppression de vos données, il se peut que nous devions conserver certaines informations à des fins juridiques ou administratives, telles que la tenue de registres, le respect des exigences en matière d’exclusion, la défense ou l’introduction de réclamations juridiques, ou la détection d’activités frauduleuses.Une telle conservation sera effectuée conformément à la section « Durée de conservation de vos Renseignements personnels » ci-dessus.

Si vous exercez votre droit de suppression, ayez à l’esprit que la suppression par les tiers auxquels les informations ont été fournies peut ne pas être immédiate et que les informations supprimées peuvent subsister dans des copies de sauvegarde pendant une période raisonnable (mais ne seront pas accessibles à d’autres personnes).

_Demande d’utilisation restreinte de vos Renseignements personnels_

Vous avez le droit de nous demander de restreindre l’utilisation de vos Renseignements personnels dans l’un des cas suivants :

* Vous contestez l’exactitude des informations que nous détenons à votre sujet, tandis que nous vérifions leur exactitude;
* Nous avons utilisé vos informations de manière illégale, mais vous nous demandez de restreindre leur utilisation au lieu de les effacer;
* Nous n’avons plus besoin desdites informations aux fins pour lesquelles nous les avons collectées, mais vous en avez besoin pour traiter une réclamation fondée en droit; ou
* Vous avez fait opposition à ce que nous utilisions vos informations, tandis que nous vérifions si nos motifs légitimes l’emportent sur votre droit d’opposition.

_Le droit de transférer vos Renseignements personnels à un autre prestataire de services_

Vous avez le droit de nous demander que nous transférions les Renseignements personnels que vous nous avez fournis d’une organisation à une autre, ou de vous les donner (_c’est-à-dire,_ la portabilité des données).Cela s’applique aux Renseignements personnels que nous traitons pour exécuter un contrat avec vous et aux Renseignements personnels que nous traitons sur la base de votre consentement.

_Le droit de retirer votre consentement_

Si nous obtenons votre consentement écrit pour la collecte et le traitement de vos Renseignements personnels, vous pourrez par la suite retirer ce consentement pour tout traitement ultérieur desdits renseignements.

_Le droit de déposer une plainte auprès d’une autorité de contrôle_

Si vous estimez que vos droits au titre du RGPD ont été violés, le RGPD vous donne le droit de déposer une plainte auprès de votre autorité de contrôle. Vous trouverez ci-après une liste de certaines autorités de contrôle : [Autorités de protection des données de l’EEE et de l’UE](https://ec.europa.eu/newsroom/article29/item-detail.cfm?item_id=612080); Préposé fédéral à la protection des données et à la transparence (PFPDT); [Bureau du Commissaire à l’information (ICO) du Royaume-Uni.](https://ico.org.uk/make-a-complaint/)

_Droits liés à la prise de décision automatisée_

Dans la mesure où nous prenons des décisions fondées uniquement sur un traitement automatisé, y compris le profilage, qui produisent des effets juridiques vous concernant ou qui vous affectent de manière significative, vous avez le droit de ne pas être soumis à ces décisions.

_Droit d’opposition au traitement_

Vous avez le droit de vous opposer au traitement de vos Renseignements personnels qui est basé sur des intérêts légitimes ou sur votre consentement (plutôt que lorsque la raison de leur utilisation est l’exécution d’une obligation qui vous est due en vertu d’un contrat avec nous).En cas d’opposition, nous cesserons de traiter les Renseignements personnels, à moins que nous puissions démontrer qu’il existe des motifs légitimes impérieux pour le traitement qui l’emportent sur vos intérêts, droits et libertés, ou que nous puissions démontrer que le traitement est nécessaire à l’établissement, l’exercice ou la défense de réclamations fondées en droit.Vous pouvez vous opposer au traitement de vos Renseignements personnels en nous contactant à l’aide des informations figurant dans la section « Nous contacter » ci-dessous.

**Bases légales pour le traitement de vos Renseignements personnels**

Alterra Mountain Company recueille vos Renseignements personnels pour vous fournir nos produits et nos Services; sans quoi nous ne serions pas en mesure de traiter les transactions que vous demandez.Nous ne traiterons vos Renseignements personnels que si nous avons une base légale pour le faire.Si vous vous trouvez dans un État de l’UE, dans un État de l’EEE, au R-U ou en Suisse, vous avez droit à une explication des bases juridiques sur lesquelles nous nous appuyons pour traiter vos Renseignements personnels.La base légale pour la collecte et l’utilisation des Renseignements personnels décrits ci-dessus dépendra des Renseignements personnels concernés et du contexte spécifique dans lequel nous les collectons, comme indiqué ci-dessous.

* **Consentement.**Nous pouvons traiter vos renseignements personnels sur la base de votre consentement, par exemple lorsque vous achetez un service ou nous demandez de vous envoyer certains types de communications marketing.Vous avez le droit de retirer votre consentement à tout moment sans que cela n’affecte la légalité du traitement fondé sur le consentement avant son retrait.
    * **Consentement des enfants.** Nous ne traitons pas sciemment les données de personnes résidant dans l’UE, dans l’EEE, au R-U ou en Suisse qui sont âgées de moins de 16 ans sans un consentement parental raisonnablement vérifié.

* **Nos intérêts légitimes.**Nous pouvons traiter vos renseignements personnels si cela est nécessaire pour nos intérêts légitimes liés à nos objectifs commerciaux découlant de votre relation avec nous, et si vos droits en tant qu’individu ne prévalent pas sur ces intérêts légitimes.À titre d’exemple, nos intérêts légitimes comprennent, sans s’y limiter, le traitement de vos renseignements personnels pour mener des activités de prévention de la fraude et des activités visant à accroîtrez la sécurité du réseau et de l’information, identifier les tendances d’utilisation, déterminer l’efficacité des campagnes promotionnelles, développer nos activités commerciales et améliorer nos services ainsi que le contenu et la fonctionnalité de nos Services.Nos intérêts légitimes comprennent également le fait de vous fournir les produits et services que vous demandez, consultez, utiliser ou achetez et à communiquer avec vous au sujet de votre compte ou de vos transactions avec nous.

* **Pour exécuter un contrat.**Nous pouvons traiter vos renseignements personnels pour gérer et remplir nos obligations contractuelles envers vous.Nous recueillerons et traiterons également vos renseignements personnels si cela est nécessaire à l’exécution d’un contrat auquel vous êtes partie.

* **Pour répondre à une obligation légale.**Nous pouvons traiter vos renseignements personnels pour nous conformer aux obligations légales auxquelles nous sommes soumis.Il peut s’agir d’une obligation de produire des comptes audités, d’une obligation légale de partager des informations avec des organismes chargés de l’application de la loi, des autorités publiques ou gouvernementales, ou d’une obligation de se conformer à une procédure judiciaire.

* **Lorsque cela est nécessaire à l’exercice ou à la défense de réclamations fondées en droit.**Si vous présentez une réclamation à notre encontre ou que nous présentons une réclamation à votre encontre, nous sommes en droit de traiter vos renseignements personnels dans le cadre de cette réclamation.

En fonction de la situation, nous pouvons être le responsable du traitement ou le sous-traitant pour les renseignements personnels recueillis auprès des résidents de l’UE, de l’EEE, du R-U ou de la Suisse.Si vous avez des questions ou si vous avez besoin d’informations supplémentaires concernant la base juridique de notre collecte de vos renseignements personnels pour toute activité de traitement spécifique, veuillez nous contacter en utilisant les informations dans la section « Nous contacter » ci-dessous.

**Transferts transfrontaliers de Renseignements personnels**

Nos Services sont offerts aux États-Unis.Les renseignements personnels que vous fournissez dans l’UE, dans un Etats de l’EEE, au R-U ou en Suisse peuvent être transférés aux États-Unis.Les États-Unis ne disposent pas de décision ou de règlement sur l’adéquation.Le RGPD autorise ces transferts lorsqu’ils sont nécessaires à l’exécution d’un contrat entre vous et nous, si nous obtenons votre consentement explicite à un tel transfert, ou s’il est dans notre intérêt légitime de transférer les renseignements personnels.Les lois des États-Unis peuvent ne pas être aussi protectrices que le RGPD ou les lois d’autres juridictions dans lesquelles vous pouvez vous trouver.Si nous transférons des renseignements personnels depuis l’UE, l’EEE, le R-U ou la Suisse, ou depuis un autre pays ayant des obligations de transfert transfrontalier, nous fournirons une garantie appropriée, telle que l’utilisation de clauses contractuelles standard.

Pour obtenir une copie de la ou des sauvegardes, veuillez nous contacter à l’aide des informations fournies dans la section « Nous contacter ».

**12\. LIENS TIERS**

Nous pouvons inclure des liens vers des sites tiers sur nos sites Web. Lorsque nous fournissons des liens, nous le faisons uniquement pour des raisons de commodité et nous ne sommes pas raisonnables du contenu des sites Web de tiers ou des liens qu’ils contiennent.Lorsque vous cliquez sur ces liens tiers, vous quittez notre site Web. La présente Politique ne s’applique pas aux sites tiers ni aux informations que vous fournissez sur ces sites.Nous ne sommes pas responsables et n’assumons aucune responsabilité pour les informations recueillies, stockées ou utilisées par des tiers à la suite de votre visite sur des sites Web de tiers.Nous vous conseillons également de lire attentivement l’avis de confidentialité des sites Web sur lesquels vous choisissez de vous rendre.

**13\. MODIFICATION DE LA POLITIQUE**

La présente Politique est sujette à changement et peut être complétée ou modifiée à tout moment. Nous vous conseillons de consulter régulièrement ce site pour vous tenir au courant des modifications apportées à la présente Politique. Si des modifications importantes sont apportées, nous vous en informerons en inscrivant un avis sur notre site Web [https://www.alterramtnco.com/privacy-policy.](https://www.alterramtnco.com/privacy-policy) Votre utilisation ininterrompue de nos Services vaut acceptation de la version la plus récente de la présente Politique.

**14\. NOUS CONTACTER**

Si vous avez des questions concernant nos pratiques en matière de confidentialité, vous pouvez nous contacter à l’adresse suivante :

Courrier :

Alterra Mountain Company

3501 Wazee Street, Suite 400

Denver, CO 80216

A l’attention de : Chef de la protection de la vie privée

Téléphone: 1-866-675-7529 (sans frais en Amérique du Nord)

Courriel: [yourprivacy@alterramtnco.com](mailto:yourprivacy@alterramtnco.com)

* Do Not Sell My Personal Information

© Alterra Mountain Company, 3501 Wazee St #400, Denver, CO 80216, (303) 749-8200
